Okay. So great to see everyone back for lecture four of the class.
好的。很高兴看到大家回来上课第四讲。
Um, so, for lec,
嗯，对于lec，
for today's lecture, um,
对于今天的演讲，嗯，
what I want to do for most of the time is actually
实际上，我大部分时间都想做的事情
get into the heart of these ideas of having
深入了解这些想法
the backpropagation algorithm for neural nets and how we can construct
神经网络的反向传播算法以及我们如何构建
computation graphs that allow sufficiently to do backpropagation,
计算图表，足以进行反向传播，
neural nets to train the neural nets.
神经网络训练神经网络。
So, overall, um, this is sort of what I plan to do it today.
总的来说，嗯，这就是我今天计划做的事情。
So, at the end of last lecture,
所以，在上次讲座结束时，
I slightly ran out of time and I started mumbling and waving my hands about the,
我有点没时间了，我开始喃喃自语，挥手示意，
um, doing the derivatives with respect to the weight gradients.
嗯，做关于重量梯度的衍生物。
So, I kinda of wanted to do that but again.
所以，我有点想再这样做。
So hopefully it actually communicates slightly better.
所以希望它实际上传达得更好。
So, we'll do that and talk a bit more about sort of just tips for doing matrix gradients,
所以，我们会这样做，并谈谈有关做矩阵渐变的一些技巧，
um, and a particular issue that comes up with word vectors.
嗯，以及提出单词向量的特定问题。
And so then the main part of the class,
那么课程的主要部分，
we'll be talking about the backpropagation algorithm
我们将讨论反向传播算法
and how it runs over computation graphs.
以及它如何在计算图上运行。
Um, and then for the last part of the class,
嗯，然后是课程的最后一部分，
um, is I'm not going to hide that, um,
嗯，我不会隐瞒那个，嗯，
this is sort of just a grab bag of miscellaneous stuff you should
这有点像你应该的杂物
know about neural networks and training neural networks.
了解神经网络和训练神经网络。
Um, like, I think,
嗯，我想，
you know we dream of a future of artificial intelligence where our machines are
你知道我们梦想着我们的机器所在的人工智能的未来
really intelligent and you can just say to them this is the data and this is my problem,
非常聪明，你可以告诉他们这是数据，这是我的问题，
go and train me a model and it might work.
去训练我一个模型，它可能会工作。
Um, and in some future world,
嗯，在未来的某个世界，
that may be  [NOISE] that comes along.
那可能是[NOISE]。
It's something that's certainly being actively
这肯定是积极的
researched at the moment under the topic of Auto ML.
目前在Auto ML主题下进行了研究。
I guess the question is whether it turns out that Auto ML was a scalable solution or
我想问的问题是，事实证明Auto ML是一个可扩展的解决方案
the climate change consequences of Auto ML techniques are
Auto ML技术的气候变化后果是
sufficiently bad that someone actually decides that these much lower power,
足够糟糕，有人实际上决定这些低得多的力量，
um, neural systems might actually be better still for doing some parts of the problem.
嗯，神经系统实际上可能更好地解决问题的某些部分。
But anyway, either way we're not really there yet.
但无论如何，无论如何，我们还没有真正存在。
And the fact of the matter is,
事实是，
when you're training neural networks,
当你训练神经网络时，
there's just a whole bunch of stuff you have to know about
你必须要了解一大堆东西
initialization and nonlinearities and learning rates and so on.
初始化和非线性以及学习率等。
And, you know, when I taught this class
而且，你知道，当我教这门课时
last time I somehow thought that people would pick this up by osmosis.
上次我不知何故认为人们会通过渗透来接受这个。
That if we gave starter,
如果我们给了首发，
cut code to people and now start
切码给人，现在开始
a code we initialized how matrices and we set our learning rates,
一个代码，我们初始化了矩阵，我们设置了学习率，
that by osmosis people would understand that's what you have to do and do it.
通过渗透，人们会明白这是你必须做的事情并做到这一点。
Um, it didn't really sort of teach in class the practical tips and tricks enough,
嗯，它真的没有在课堂上教授足够的实用技巧和窍门，
but it was perfectly obvious that when we got to
但是当我们到达时，这是非常明显的
final project time that at least for quite a few people, osmosis hadn't worked.
最后的项目时间，至少对于很多人来说，渗透不起作用。
Um, so this time,
嗯，这次，
[LAUGHTER] I'm at least wanting to spend a few minutes on that
[大笑]我至少想花几分钟时间
and at least point out some other things that are important.
并至少指出一些重要的事情。
And, I mean just in general,
而且，我的意思是一般的，
you know the reality of 2018, deep learning, no,
你知道2018年的现实，深度学习，不，
wait, it's 2019 now, 2019, um,
等等，现在是2019年，2019年，嗯，
deep learning, is deep learning is still kind of a craft.
深度学习，深度学习仍然是一种手艺。
There's quite a bit you have to know of techniques of doing things that lead
你必须知道有关做事的技巧
neural net training to work successfully as
神经网络训练成功地工作
opposed to your models failing to work successfully.
反对你的模型未能成功运作。
Okay. One final announcement and I go in to it.
好的。一个最后的公告，我进入它。
Um, so, we've sort of been doing some further working on Office,
嗯，我们已经在Office上做了一些进一步的工作，
our placement and I guess there are sort of multiple issues which
我们的位置，我想有多种问题
include the opportunities for local ICPD students without Stanford IDs.
包括没有斯坦福身份证的当地人发会议学生的机会。
We have to, um,
我们必须，嗯，
get, um, to office hours.
得到，嗯，到办公时间。
So for the Thursday night office hour,
所以对于周四晚办公时间，
um, that's after this class,
嗯，这是在这堂课之后，
if you'd like to go and talk about,
如果你想去谈谈，
um, the second homework, um,
嗯，第二个作业，嗯，
the Thursday night office hour is going to be in Thorton- Thornton 110.
星期四晚上办公时间将在Thorton- Thornton 110。
Um, now I didn't know where Thornton was.
嗯，现在我不知道桑顿在哪里。
It made more sense to me when I translated that as that's the old terman annex,
当我把它翻译成旧的terman附件时，对我来说更有意义，
but that's probably just showing my age since probably none
但这可能只是显示我的年龄，因为可能没有
of you remember when they used to be a building called Terman.
你记得他们曾经是一个名叫特曼的建筑物。
So that probably doesn't help you either.
所以这可能对你没有帮助。
Um, but you know,
嗯，但是你知道，
if you're heading, right,
如果你正在前进，对，
I don't know which direction we're facing.
我不知道我们面临的方向。
If you're heading that way I guess
如果你正朝着这个方向前进，我猜
and if you know where the Papua New Guinea Sculpture Garden is, um, the,
如果你知道巴布亚新几内亚雕塑园在哪里，嗯，
the sort of open grassy area before you get to the Papua New Guinea Sculpture Garden,
在你到达巴布亚新几内亚雕塑花园之前的那种开阔的草地区，
that's where Terman used to be and the building that still stands in there is Thornton.
这就是特曼过去的地方，而桑顿的建筑仍然存在。
Um, Thornton 110 um tonight.
嗯，桑顿今晚110分。
I think it starts at 6:30,
我认为它从6:30开始，
right? 6:30 to nine.
对？ 6:30到9点。
Okay. Right. So, let me just finish off where we were last time.
好的。对。所以，让我告诉我们上次的情况。
So remember we had this window of five words and then we're
所以记住我们有五个单词的窗口，然后我们就是
putting it through a neural net layer of C equals WX plus B,
把它穿过C的神经网络层等于WX加B，
non-linearity of H equals F of X,
H的非线性等于X的F，
and then we're, um,
然后我们是，嗯，
going to just get a score as to whether this has in its center [NOISE]
只是得到一个关于这是否在其中心的评分[NOISE]
named entity like Paris which is sort of
像巴黎这样的命名实体
taking this dot product of a vector times the hidden layer.
将矢量的这个点积乘以隐藏层。
So this was our model,
所以这是我们的模型，
and then we are wanting to work out partial derivatives of S with
然后我们想要找出S的偏导数
respect to all of our variables and we did various of the cases,
尊重我们所有的变量，我们做了各种各样的案例，
but one we hadn't yet done is the weights,
但我们还没有做过的是重量，
and the weight through all of this neural net layer here.
这里通过所有这个神经网络层的权重。
Okay. So, chain rule, um,
好的。所以，链规则，嗯，
the partial of ds dw is DS times HD,
ds dw的部分是DS倍HD，
um, dHDZ times DZ, DW.
嗯，dHDZ倍DZ，DW。
And well, if you remember last time,
好吧，如果你记得上次，
we had sort of done some computation of what those first two,
我们做了一些计算前两个，
um, partial derivatives were.
嗯，偏导数是。
And we could say that we could just call
我们可以说我们可以打电话
those delta which is our error signal coming from above.
这些delta是我们从上面得到的误差信号。
And that concept of having an error signal coming from above is
从上面得到错误信号的概念是
something I'll get back to in the main part of
我会回到主要部分的东西
the lecture and a sort of a central notion.
讲座和一种中心概念。
But the bit we hadn't dealt with is this dz,
但我们没有处理的是这个dz，
dw and we started to look at that and I made the argument, um,
dw，我们开始关注那个，我提出了论点，嗯，
based on our shape convention that the shape of
根据我们的形状惯例，形状
that should be the same shape as our W matrix.
它应该与我们的W矩阵具有相同的形状。
So it should be, um,
所以它应该是，嗯，
same in times M shape as this W matrix.
与W矩阵相同的M次形状。
So we want to work out the partial of Z by W which is the same as this,
所以我们想要计算W的部分Z，这与此相同，
um, [NOISE] dwx plus b, dw.
嗯，[NOISE] dwx加b，dw。
And so we want to work out what that derivative is.
所以我们想弄清楚那个衍生物是什么。
Um, and if that's not obvious,
嗯，如果那不明显，
one way to think about it is to go back to this elements of the matrix
考虑它的一种方法是回到矩阵的这些元素
and actually first off work it out element-wise and think out what it should be,
实际上，首先要按照元素的方式进行工作，并想出它应该是什么，
and then once you've thought out what it should be, um,
然后一旦你想出它应该是什么，嗯，
to rewrite it back in matrix form to give the compact answer.
以矩阵形式重写它以给出紧凑的答案。
So what we have is we have the inputs here and a biased term
所以我们拥有的是这里的输入和有偏见的术语
and we're going to do the matrix multiply it this vector to produce these.
我们要做矩阵乘以这个向量来产生这些。
And if you think about what's happening there,
如果你想一想那里发生了什么，
so we've got this matrix of weights and for a particular weight,
所以我们有这个重量矩阵和特定的重量，
a weight is first index is going to correspond to a position in
权重是第一个索引将对应于中的位置
the hidden layer and its second index is going to
隐藏层及其第二个索引即将发生
correspond to a position in the input vector.
对应于输入向量中的位置。
And one weight in the matrix ends up being
矩阵中的一个权重最终成为
part of what's used to compute one element of the hidden layer.
用于计算隐藏层的一个元素的部分内容。
So, the one element of the hidden layer you're taking, um,
所以，你正在采取隐藏层的一个元素，嗯，
a row of the matrix and you're multiplying it by
矩阵的一行，你将它乘以
the components of this vector so they sum together when the bias
这个向量的组成部分使它们在偏差时相加
is added on but one element of the matrix is sort of only being
添加，但矩阵的一个元素只是一种
used in the computation between one element of the,
用于计算之间的一个元素，
um, important one element of the hidden vector.
嗯，隐藏矢量的重要一个元素。
Okay. So, well, that means, um,
好的。所以，嗯，这意味着，嗯，
if we're thinking about what's the partial derivative with respect to WIJ, well,
如果我们考虑什么是关于WIJ的偏导数，那么，
it's only contributing to ZI and it's only,
它只对ZI有贡献而且它是唯一的，
it's only doing anything with XJ.
它只对XJ做任何事情。
So, that we end up with,
所以，我们最终得到了，
we're getting the partial with respect to WIJ,
我们对WIJ有所了解，
we can work that out with respect to,
我们可以解决这个问题，
just to respect to ZI.
只是为了尊重ZI。
And when we're going to look at this multiplication here,
当我们在这里看看这个乘法时，
what we're ending up is this sort of sum of terms WIK times
我们最终得到的是WIK时代这类术语的总和
Xk where there's sort of weights in that row
Xk那里有那种权重
of the matrix going across the positions of the vector.
穿过矢量位置的矩阵。
So the only position in which WIJ is used is multiplying, um, by XJ.
因此，使用WIJ的唯一位置是乘以XJ。
And at that point,
那时，
what we have in terms of sort of,
我们在种类方面有什么，
in our basic one variable doing a differentiation,
在我们的基本变量中进行区分，
this is just like we have 3x,
这就像我们有3倍，
um, and we say what's the derivative of 3x?
嗯，我们说3x的衍生物是什么？
Actually X is confusing,
实际上X很混乱，
so I shouldn't say that.
所以我不应该这么说。
Is like we have three W and what's the derivative of three W with respect to W?
就像我们有三个W和三个W相对于W的衍生物是什么？
It's three, right?
这是三个，对吗？
So, that we've have a term here which is what would have been W,
所以，我们这里有一个术语，就是W，
will be WIJ times XJ,
将是WIJ次XJ，
and its derivative with respect to WIJ is just XJ.
它与WIJ的衍生物只是XJ。
Does that makes sense?
这有道理吗？
Everyone believe it?
大家都相信吗？
[NOISE] Fingers crossed.
[NOISE]手指交叉。
Okay. Um, so, so for one element of this matrix,
好的。嗯，所以，对于这个矩阵的一个元素，
we're just getting out XJ.
我们刚刚离开XJ。
And at that point,
那时，
um, we say, um,
嗯，我们说，嗯，
well of course we want to know what the Jacobian is for the full matrix W. Well,
当然，我们想知道Jacobian对于完整矩阵W是什么。嗯，
if you start thinking about it,
如果你开始考虑它，
this argument applies to every cell.
这个论点适用于每个细胞。
So, that for every,
所以，每一个，
um, cell of, um,
嗯，嗯，嗯，
the Jacobian for W,
W的雅可比，
um, it's going to be XJ.
嗯，这将是XJ。
So, that means, um,
所以，这意味着，嗯，
we're just going to be able to make use of that in calculating our Jacobian.
我们将能够在计算我们的雅可比行列时使用它。
So, the derivative for a single WIJ is delta IXJ and that's true for all cells.
因此，单个WIJ的衍生物是delta IXJ，对所有细胞都是如此。
So we wanted to have a matrix for our Jacobian which has delta I,
所以我们希望我们的雅可比矩阵有一个delta I，
um, XJ in every cell of it.
嗯，XJ在它的每个单元格中。
And the way we can create that is by using an outer products.
我们创造的方式就是使用外部产品。
So, if we have a row vector of the deltas,
所以，如果我们有一个增量的行向量，
the error signals from above and a column,
来自上方和列的错误信号，
right, I said that wrong, sorry.
对，我说错了，对不起。
If we have a column of the delta error signals
如果我们有一列delta错误信号
from above and we have a row of X transfers vectors,
从上面我们有一排X传输向量，
um, when we multiply those together we get the outer product
嗯，当我们将它们相乘时，我们得到外部产品
and we get delta IXJ in each cell and that is our Jacobian answer,
我们在每个单元格中得到delta IXJ，这就是我们的雅可比答案，
um, for working out,
嗯，为了锻炼，
um, the delta S delta W that we started off with at the beginning.
嗯，我们在开始时开始的delta S delta W.
Okay. And this, um,
好的。这个，嗯，
and we get this form where it's a multiplication of
我们得到这个形式，它是一个乘法
an error signal from above and our computed local gradient signal.
来自上方的误差信号和我们计算出的局部梯度信号。
And that's the pattern that we're going to see over and over
这就是我们一遍又一遍地看到的模式
again and that will exploit and our computation graphs.
再次，这将利用和我们的计算图。
Okay, all good?
好的，一切都好吗？
Okay. Um, so, here's just,
好的。嗯，所以，这里只是，
um, here's homework two.
嗯，这是两个作业。
You're meant to do some of this stuff.
你打算做一些这样的事情。
Um, here are just over a couple of collected tips,
嗯，这里有几个收集的提示，
um, which I hope will help.
嗯，我希望能帮到你。
I mean keeping here track of your variables and
我的意思是跟踪你的变量和
their dimensionality is really useful because we
他们的维度非常有用，因为我们
just can work out what the dimensionality of things should be.
只是可以弄清楚事物的维度应该是什么。
You're often kind of halfway there.
你经常在那里。
I mean basically what you're doing is sort of
我的意思是基本上你正在做的事情
applying the chain rule over and over again.
一遍又一遍地应用链规则。
It always looks like this.
它看起来总是这样。
Um, but doing it in this sort of matrix calculus sense of the chain rule.
嗯，但是在链规则的这种矩阵微积分意义上这样做。
Um, in the homework you have to do a softmax,
嗯，在做作业时你必须做一个softmax，
which we haven't done in class.
我们没有在课堂上做过。
Um, something that I think you'll find useful,
嗯，我认为你会发现有用的东西，
if you want to break apart the softmax is to consider two cases.
如果你想分手，softmax就要考虑两种情况。
One, the case is to when you're working it out for the correct class.
其中一个案例是当你正在为正确的班级工作时。
And then, the other case is for all the other incorrect classes.
然后，另一种情况是针对所有其他不正确的类。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
Um, in the the little derivation,
嗯，在小小的推导中，
I did before, I said well,
我之前做过，我说得好，
let's work out an element-wise partial
让我们找出一个元素方面的部分
derivative because that should give me some sense of what's going on,
衍生因为这应该让我对正在发生的事情有所了解，
what the answer is.
答案是什么。
I think that can be a really good thing to do
我认为这可能是一件非常好的事情
if you're getting confused by matrix calculus.
如果你对矩阵演算感到困惑。
And I sort of,
我有点儿，
um, slightly skipped past another slide.
嗯，略微跳过另一张幻灯片。
Last time that was talking about
上次谈的是
the shape convention that I talked about it for a moment that
我刚才谈到它的形状惯例
for the homeworks you can work out your answer however you want,
对于家庭作业，你可以根据自己的意愿找到答案，
you can work it out in terms of;
你可以解决这个问题;
you know numerator ordered Jacobians,
你知道分子命令雅各比人，
if that seems best to you.
如果这对你来说最好
But we'd like you to give the final answer to
但是我们希望你能给出最终答案
your assignment questions following the shape convention.
你的任务问题遵循形状约定。
So, that the derivative should be shaped in
因此，衍生品应该成形
a vector matrix in the same way as the variable,
矢量矩阵与变量相同，
with respect to which you're working out your derivatives.
关于你正在研究你的衍生品。
Okay. Um, the last little bit for finishing up this example from last time,
好的。嗯，这是上次完成这个例子的最后一点，
I want to say a little bit about,
我想说一点，
is what happens with words.
是用语言发生的事情。
And one answer is nothing different.
一个答案没有什么不同。
But another answer is they are a little bit of a special case here because,
但另一个答案是，这里有一些特殊情况因为，
you know, really we have a matrix of word vectors, right?
你知道吗，我们真的有一个单词向量矩阵，对吗？
We have a vector for each word.
我们为每个单词都有一个向量。
And so then you can think of that as sort of this matrix of word vectors,
所以你可以把它想象成这个单词向量矩阵，
which row has a different word.
哪一行有不同的词。
But we're not actually kind of connecting up
但我们实际上并没有那种联系
that matrix directly to our classifier system.
那个矩阵直接到我们的分类器系统。
Instead of that, what we're connect connecting up to the classifier system is
而不是那样，我们连接到分类器系统的连接是什么
this window and the window will have it in at five words.
这个窗口和窗口将以五个单词显示。
Most commonly they're different words.
最常见的是他们是不同的词。
But you know occasionally the same word might appear,
但你偶尔会知道同一个词可能出现，
um, in two positions in that window.
嗯，在那个窗口的两个位置。
And so, we can nevertheless do
所以，我们可以做到
exactly the same thing and continue our gradients down and say okay,
完全相同的事情，并继续我们的渐变下来，说好吧，
um, let's work out, um,
嗯，让我们锻炼，嗯，
the gradients of this word window vector.
这个词窗口向量的渐变。
And if, um, these are of dimension D we'll have this sort of 5-D, um, vector.
如果，嗯，这些是维D，我们将有这种5-D，嗯，矢量。
But, you know then what do we do about it,
但是，你知道我们该怎么做，
and the answer of what we do about it.
以及我们对此采取的措施的答案。
Is we can just sort of split this window vector into five pieces and say aha,
我们可以把这个窗口矢量分成五个部分然后说aha，
we have five updates to word vectors.
我们对单词向量有五个更新。
We're just going to go off and apply them to the word Vector Matrix.
我们将开始将它们应用于Vector Matrix这个词。
Um, and you know if we if the same word occurs twice,
嗯，你知道我们是否同一个词出现两次，
um, in that window we literally apply both of the updates.
嗯，在那个窗口中我们确实应用了两个更新。
So, it gets updated twice or maybe
所以，它会更新两次或者更新
actually you want to sum them first and then do the update once but yeah,
实际上你想先将它们相加，然后进行一次更新，但是，是的，
that's a technical issue.
这是一个技术问题。
Um, so what that actually means is that we're extremely sparsely
嗯，所以这实际上意味着我们非常稀疏
updating the word Vector Matrix because most of
更新单词Vector Matrix，因为大多数
the word Vector Matrix will be unchanged and just a few rows of that,
Vector Matrix这个词将保持不变，只有几行，
um, will be being updated.
嗯，将会更新。
And if- um, soon we're going to be here doing stuff with PyTorch
如果 - 很快，我们很快就会在这里用PyTorch做事
Um, and if you poke around Pytorch it even has some special stuff.
嗯，如果你在Pytorch周围逛逛，它甚至会有一些特殊的东西。
Um, look for things like Sparse SGD for meaning
嗯，寻找像Sparse SGD这样的东西
that you're sort of doing a very sparse updating like that.
你有点像这样进行非常稀疏的更新。
Um, but there's one other sort of interesting thing that you should know about.
嗯，但还有一件你应该知道的有趣的事情。
For a lot of um,
对于很多人来说，
things that you do is just what actually happens if we push
你做的事情就是如果我们推动实际发生的事情
down these gradients into our word vectors.
将这些渐变降低到我们的单词向量中。
Well, the idea is no,
好吧，这个想法不是，
if we do that would be just like all other neural net learning,
如果我们这样做就像所有其他神经网络学习一样
that we will sort of in principle say move the word vectors around in such a way
我们原则上会说以这种方式移动单词向量
as they're more useful in helping determine
因为它们在帮助确定方面更有用
named entity classification in this case because that was our motivating example.
在这种情况下命名实体分类，因为这是我们的动机示例。
Um, so you know it might for example learn that the word in is
嗯，所以你知道它可能会例如知道单词in
a very good indicator of a named entity fall or sorry the place name following.
指定实体的一个非常好的指标，或者遗憾地跟随地名。
So, after n you often get London, Paris et cetera.
所以，经过n经常你得到伦敦，巴黎等等。
Right, so it's sort of got a special behavior that
是的，所以它有一种特殊的行为
other prepositions don't as being a good location indicator.
其他介词不是一个好的位置指示器。
And so, it could sort of um,
所以，它可能有点嗯，
move it's location around and say here are words that are
移动它的位置，并说这里是单词
good location indicators and therefore help our classifier work even better.
良好的位置指标，因此有助于我们的分类器更好地工作。
So, in principle that's good and it's a good thing to do,
所以，原则上这很好，这是一件好事，
to update word vectors to help you perform better on
更新单词向量以帮助您更好地执行
a supervised task such as this Named Entity Recognition classification.
受监督的任务，例如此命名实体识别分类。
But, there's a catch which is that it doesn't always work actually.
但是，有一个问题是它实际上并不总是有效。
And so, why doesn't it always work?
那么，为什么它总是不起作用？
Well, suppose that we're training a classifier.
好吧，假设我们正在训练分类器。
Um, you know it could be the one I just did or a softmax or logistic regression.
嗯，你知道它可能是我刚刚做过的那个，或者是softmax或逻辑回归。
And we wanting to classify um,
我们想要分类，
movie reviews sentiment for positive or negative.
电影评论积极或消极的情绪。
Well, you know if we have trained our word vectors,
好吧，你知道我们是否训练了我们的单词向量，
we've got some word vector space and maybe in the word vector space, um, TV,
我们有一些单词向量空间，也许在单词向量空间，嗯，电视，
telly and television are all very close
电视和电视都非常接近
together because they mean basically the same thing.
因为他们的意思基本相同。
So, that's great, our word vectors are good.
所以，这很好，我们的单词向量很好。
But, well suppose it was the case,
但是，假设情况确实如此，
that in our training data for our classifier.
在我们的分类器的训练数据中。
So, this is our training data for movie sentiment review.
所以，这是我们的电影情绪评论培训数据。
We had the word TV and telly but we didn't have the word television.
我们有电视和电视这个词，但我们没有电视这个词。
Well, then what's going to happen,
好吧，接下来会发生什么，
is well while we try and train our sentiment classifier,
在我们尝试和训练我们的情绪分类器的同时，
if we push gradient back down into the word vectors what's likely to happen
如果我们将梯度向下推入单词向量中，那么可能会发生什么
is that it will move around the word vectors of the words we saw in the training data.
它将围绕我们在训练数据中看到的单词的向量移动。
But, necessarily television's not moving, right?
但是，电视一定不动，对吧？
Because we're only pushing gradient down to words that are in our training data.
因为我们只是将渐变推向训练数据中的单词。
So, this word goes nowhere,
所以，这个词无处可去，
so it just stays where it was all along.
所以它一直保持原样。
So, if the result of our training is words get moved around.
所以，如果我们训练的结果是文字被移动。
So, here a good words for indicating negative sentiment, um,
所以，这里有一个表示负面情绪的好词，嗯，
will actually if at test time,
实际上，如果在测试时，
when we're running our model,
当我们运行我们的模型时，
if we evaluate on a sentence with television in it,
如果我们评估一个带有电视的句子，
it's actually going to give the wrong answer.
它实际上会给出错误的答案。
Whereas if we haven't changed the word vectors at all and had just left
然而，如果我们根本没有更改单词向量而刚刚离开
them where our word embedding learning system put them.
他们我们的单词嵌入学习系统的地方。
Then it would have said television,
然后会说电视，
that's a word that means about the same as TV or telly.
这是一个与电视或电视大致相同的词。
I should treat it the same and
我应该对待它
my sentiment classifier and it would actually do a better job.
我的情绪分类器，它实际上会做得更好。
So, it's sort of two-sided whether you gain by training word vectors.
因此，无论您是通过训练单词向量获得的，它都是双面的。
And so, this is a summary um, that says;
所以，这是一个总结嗯，说;
that it's two sided and practically what you should do.
它是双面的，几乎是你应该做的。
So, the first choice is G is a good idea to use pre-trained word vectors like
所以，第一个选择是G是一个好主意，使用预先训练过的单词向量
the word2vec vectors that you used in assignment one or
您在作业中使用的word2vec向量或
using the training methods that you're doing right now for homework two.
使用你现在正在做的功课训练方法。
And the answer that is almost always yes.
答案几乎总是肯定的。
And the reason for that is this word vector training methods are
原因就是这个词矢量训练方法是
extremely easy to run on billions of words of texts.
非常容易在数十亿字的文字上运行。
So, we you know train these models like [inaudible] on billions or tens of billions of words.
所以，我们知道像[音频不清晰]训练这些模型的数十亿或数十亿字。
And it's easy to do that for two reasons.
由于两个原因，这很容易做到。
Firstly, because the training algorithms are very simple, right?
首先，因为训练算法非常简单，对吧？
That um, the word2vec training algorithms skip grams very simple algorithm.
那个，word2vec训练算法跳过克非常简单的算法。
Secondly; because we don't need any expensive resources,
其次;因为我们不需要任何昂贵的资源，
all or we need as a big pile of text documents and we can run it on them.
所有或我们需要作为一大堆文本文档，我们可以在它们上运行它。
So, really easy to run it on,
所以，真的很容易运行它，
you know five or 50 billion words.
你知道五五百亿字。
Whereas, you know, we can't do that for most of the classifiers that we
然而，你知道，我们不能为我们的大多数分类器做到这一点
want to build because if it's something
想要建立，因为如果它是什么
I sentiment classifier or a named entity recognizer,
我感情分类器或命名实体识别器，
we need labeled training data to train
我们需要标记的训练数据来训练
our classifier and then we ask someone how many words have labeled training data,
我们的分类器然后我们问某人有多少单词标记了训练数据，
do you have for named entity recognition and they give this back
你有没有得到命名实体的认可，他们会给予回报
a number like 300,000 words or one million words, right.
对，就像30万字或一百万字一样的数字。
It's orders a magnitude smaller.
它的订单量要小一些。
Okay. Um. So, therefore,
好的。嗯。因此，
we can gain using pre-trained word vectors,
我们可以使用预先训练的单词向量，
because they know about all the words that aren't
因为他们知道所有不是的词
now supervised, classifies training data.
现在受到监督，对培训数据进行分类。
And they also know much more about the words that actually
而且他们也更了解实际上的话
are in the training data, but only rarely.
在训练数据中，但很少。
So, the exception to that is,
所以，例外是，
if you have hundreds of millions of words of data,
如果你有数亿字的数据，
then you can start off with random word vectors and go from there.
然后你可以从随机单词向量开始，然后从那里开始。
And so, a case where this is actually commonly done,
所以，这实际上通常是这样的，
is for machine translation,
用于机器翻译，
which we do later in the class.
我们后来在课堂上做的。
It's relatively easy for
它相对容易
large languages to get hundreds of millions of words of translated text.
大型语言可以获得数亿字的翻译文本。
If you wanted to build something,
如果你想建造一些东西，
like a German- English or Chinese-English machine translation system.
像德语 - 英语或中英文机器翻译系统。
Not hard to get 150 million words of translated texts.
不难获得1,5亿字的翻译文本。
And so, that's sort of sufficiently much data,
所以，那是一种足够多的数据，
that people commonly just start with word vectors, um,
人们通常只是从单词向量开始，嗯，
being randomly initialized and start training,
随机初始化并开始训练，
um, their translation system.
嗯，他们的翻译系统。
Okay. So then the second question is, okay.
好的。那么第二个问题是，好的。
I'm using pre-trained word vectors.
我正在使用预先训练过的单词向量。
Um, when I train my supervised classifier,
嗯，当我训练我的监督分类器时，
should I push gradients down into the word vectors and up, and update them?
我应该将渐变向下推入单词向量和向上，并更新它们吗？
Which is often referred to as fine tuning the word vectors, um,
这通常被称为微调单词向量，嗯，
or should I not,
或者我不应该，
should I just sort of throw away
我应该扔掉
those gradients and not push them down into the word vectors?
那些渐变而不是把它们推到单词向量中？
And you know, the answer to that is it depends,
你知道，答案就是取决于，
and it just depends on the size.
它只取决于尺寸。
So, if you only have a small training data set, um, typically,
所以，如果你只有一个小的训练数据集，嗯，通常，
it's best to just treat the pre-trained word vectors as fixed,
最好只将经过预先训练的单词向量视为固定，
um, and not do any updating of them at all.
嗯，根本不做任何更新。
If you have a large data set,
如果您有大型数据集，
then you can normally gain by doing fine tuning of the word vectors.
那么你通常可以通过对单词向量进行微调来获得。
And of course, the answer here,
当然，答案在这里，
is what counts as large.
重要的是什么。
Um, you know, if certainly,
嗯，你知道，如果肯定的话，
if you're down in the regime of 100 thousand words,
如果你在10万字的政权下来，
a couple of hundred thousand words, you're small.
几十万字，你很小。
If you're starting to be over a million words,
如果你开始超过一百万字，
then maybe you're large.
那么也许你很大。
But you know, on practice, people do it both ways and see which number is higher,
但是你知道，在实践中，人们都是这样做，看看哪个数字更高，
and that's what they stick with.
这就是他们坚持的。
Um. Yes. Um, then, the sort of,
嗯。是。嗯，那么，那种，
there's the sort of point here that is just worth underlying is " Yes",
这里有一点值得深思的是“是”，
so on principle, we can back-propagate this gradient to every variable in our model.
所以原则上，我们可以将此渐变反向传播到模型中的每个变量。
Um, it's actually a theorem that we can arbitrarily
嗯，这实际上是一个我们可以任意的定理
decide to throw any subset of those gradients away,
决定扔掉那些渐变的任何子集，
and we are still improving the log-likelihood of our model, all right?
我们仍在改进模型的对数似然性，好吗？
It kind of can't be inconsistent.
它有点不一致。
You can just sort of pick some subset and say only
你可以选择一些子集并只说
train those 37 and throw away all the rest.
训练那些37并扔掉所有其余的。
And the algorithm will still improve,
算法仍然会改进，
um, the log-likelihood of the model.
嗯，模型的对数似然。
Perhaps not by as much as if you trained the rest of the variables,
也许不是因为你训练了其余的变量，
as well, um, but yes,
嗯，但是，是的，
it can't actually do any harm not to train anything.
不训练任何东西实际上不会造成任何伤害。
Um, that's one of the reasons why often people don't notice bugs in their code, as well.
嗯，这也是人们常常没有注意到代码中的错误的原因之一。
It is because if your code is kind of broken
这是因为如果你的代码有点破碎
and only half of the variables are being updated,
并且只有一半的变量正在更新，
it will still seem to be training something and improving.
它似乎仍然会训练一些东西并改进。
Um. It's just not doing as well as it could be doing,
嗯。它只是没有做得那么好，
if you've coded correctly.
如果你编码正确的话。
Okay. Um, so, at this point, um,
好的。嗯，在这一点上，嗯，
that's sort of, um,
那是那种，嗯，
almost shown you back propagation, right?
几乎向你展示了回传，对吗？
So, back-propagation is really taking derivatives with a generalized chain rule,
因此，反向传播实际上是采用广义链规则的衍生物，
with the one further trick which we sort of represented with that delta,
还有一个我们用这个delta代表的技巧，
which is G. You want to be, um,
这是G.你想成为，嗯，
clever in doing this, so,
聪明的这样做，所以，
you minimize computation by reusing shared stuff.
通过重用共享内容来最小化计算。
Um, but now what I want to move on is to sort of look at how we can do
嗯，但现在我想要继续看看我们如何做
that much more systematically, which is this idea.
更系统地说，这就是这个想法。
We have a computation graph and we're going to run
我们有一个计算图，我们将要运行
a back-propagation algorithm through the computation graph.
通过计算图的反向传播算法。
So, this is kind of like an abstracts syntax tree,
所以，这有点像摘要语法树，
expression tree that you might see in a compiler's class,
您可能在编译器的类中看到的表达式树，
or something like that, right?
或类似的东西，对吧？
So, when we have an arithmetic expression of the kind that we're going to compute,
所以，当我们有一个我们要计算的那种算术表达式时，
we can make this tipped over on its side tree representation.
我们可以在它的侧面树表示上进行翻转。
So, we've got the X and W variables,
所以，我们有X和W变量，
we're going to multiply them.
我们要增加它们。
There's the B variable,
有B变量，
we're going to add it to the previous partial result.
我们要将它添加到之前的部分结果中。
We're going to stick it through our non-linearity F
我们将通过我们的非线性F坚持下去
and then we're going to multiply it by U.
然后我们将它乘以U.
And that was the computation,
那是计算，
that we're doing in our neural network.
我们在神经网络中做的事情。
So, um the source nodes or inputs,
那么，是源节点或输入，
the interior nodes of this tree are operations.
这棵树的内部节点是操作。
And then we've got these edges that pass along the results of our computation.
然后我们将这些边缘传递给我们的计算结果。
And so, this is the computation graph for precisely the example
因此，这是精确示例的计算图
I've been doing for the last lecture [NOISE].
我一直在做最后一次演讲[NOISE]。
Okay, so there are two things that we want to be able to do.
好的，所以我们希望能够做两件事。
The first one is,
第一个是，
we want to be able to start with these variables and do this computation,
我们希望能够从这些变量开始并进行此计算，
and calculate what S is.
并计算S是什么。
That's the part that's dead simple,
这是死的简单的部分，
that's referred to as forward propagation.
这被称为前向传播。
So, forward propagation is just expression evaluation,
所以，前向传播只是表达式评估，
as you do in any any programming in language interpreter.
就像你在语言翻译中的任何编程一样。
Um, that's not hard at all.
嗯，这根本不难。
Um, but the difference here is, "Hey,
嗯，但这里的区别是，“嘿，
we want to do a learning algorithm" so we're going to do the opposite of that, as well.
我们想要做一个学习算法“所以我们也会做相反的事情。
What we want to be able to do is also backward propagation,
我们希望能够做的还是向后传播，
or back-propagation or just back-prop, it's commonly called,
或反向传播或只是反向传播，它通常被称为，
which is we want to be able to go,
这是我们想要去的，
um, from the final part.
嗯，从最后一部分开始。
The final part here.
最后一部分在这里。
And then at each step,
然后在每一步，
we want to be calculating
我们想要计算
these partial derivatives and passing them back through the graph.
这些偏导数并将它们传回图表。
And so, this was sort of the notion before that we had an error signal, right?
所以，在我们发出错误信号之前，这是一种概念，对吧？
So, we're starting from up here,
所以，我们从这里开始，
we've calculated a partial of S by Z,
我们用Z计算了S的一部分，
which is this with respect to that.
就此而言就是这个。
And so, that's sort of our calculated error signal, up to here,
所以，这是我们计算出的误差信号，到此为止，
and then we want to pass that further back, to start, um,
然后我们想再过一步，开始，嗯，
computing, um, um, gradients further back.
计算，嗯，嗯，梯度进一步回来。
Right? And we started off, um, right here,
对？我们开始了，嗯，就在这里，
with the partial of S by S. What's the partial of S by S going to be?
S的部分S由S. S的部分内容是什么？
One. Okay, yes.
一。好的，是的。
So, the rate at which S changes is the rate at which S changes.
因此，S变化的速率是S变化的速率。
So, we just start off with one,
所以，我们从一开始，
and then we want to work out how this gradient changes as we go along.
然后我们想弄清楚这个渐变如何随着我们的变化而变化。
Um, so what we're doing here is when we're working out things for one node,
嗯，我们在这里做的是当我们为一个节点制定东西时，
that a node is going to have passed in towards it upstream gradient,
一个节点将向上游渐变传递，
which is its error signal.
这是它的错误信号。
So, that's the partial of our final, f- final result,
所以，这是我们最终的f-最终结果的一部分，
which was our loss, um, by um,
这是我们的损失，嗯，嗯，
the va- variable was the output of these computation nodes.
va变量是这些计算节点的输出。
So, that's the partial of S I H, here.
那么，这就是SIH的一部分，在这里。
And then, we did some operation here.
然后，我们在这里做了一些操作。
Here's the non-linearity, but it might be something else.
这是非线性，但它可能是其他东西。
And so what we want to then work out is a downstream gradient,
那么我们想要解决的是下游梯度，
which is the partial of S by Z,
这是S by Z的部分，
which was the input to this function.
这是这个功能的输入。
And well then the question is,
那么问题是，
how do we do that?
我们怎么做？
And the answer to that is,
答案就是，
we use the chain rule, of course, right?
我们当然使用连锁规则吧？
So, at, we have a concept of a local gradients.
所以，在，我们有一个局部渐变的概念。
So, here's H as the output,
所以，这是H作为输出，
um, Z is the input.
嗯，Z是输入。
So, this function here,
那么，这个功能在这里，
this is our non-linearity, right?
这是我们的非线性，对吧？
So, this is whatever we're using as our non-linearity,
所以，这就是我们使用的非线性，
like a logistic or T and H. We calculate H in terms of Z,
像逻辑或T和H.我们用Z计算H，
and we can work out the partial of H by Z.
我们可以通过Z来计算H的部分。
So, that's our local gradient.
那么，那就是我们的局部渐变。
And so then, if we have both the upstream gradient and the local gradient.
那么，如果我们同时具有上游梯度和局部梯度。
We can then work out the downstream gradient because we know the
然后我们可以计算出下游梯度，因为我们知道了
partial of S by Z is going to be DSDH times, um, DHDZ.
S by Z的部分将是DSDH倍，嗯，DHDZ。
And so, then we'll be able to pass down the downstream gradient to the next node.
因此，我们将能够将下游梯度传递到下一个节点。
Okay. So our basic rule,
好的。所以我们的基本规则，
which is just the chain rule written in different terms
这只是用不同术语编写的链规则
is downstream gradient equals upstream gradient times local gradient.
下游梯度等于上游梯度乘以局部梯度。
Um, easy as that,um, okay.
嗯，这很容易，嗯，好的。
So, this was um,
所以，这是嗯，
the very simplest case where we have a node with one input and one output.
最简单的情况，我们有一个输入和一个输出的节点。
So, that's a function um,
那么，这是一个功能嗯，
like our logistic function.
喜欢我们的物流功能。
But, we also want to have things work out for general computation graphs.
但是，我们也希望能够解决一般计算图。
So, how are we going to do that?
那么，我们该怎么做呢？
Well, the next case is,
那么，下一个案例是，
um, what about if we have multiple inputs?
嗯，如果我们有多个输入呢？
So, if we're calculating something like Z equals W times X.
所以，如果我们计算像Z等于W乘以X的东西。
Um, where actually yes Z and X are themselves vectors and W um,
嗯，实际上是的Z和X本身就是向量和W um，
is a matrix, but we're treating X as an input and W as an input,
是矩阵，但我们将X视为输入，W视为输入，
and Z as our output, right?
和Z作为我们的输出，对吗？
We kind of group vectors and matrices together.
我们将组向量和矩阵组合在一起。
Well, if you have multiple inputs,
好吧，如果你有多个输入，
you then end up with multiple local gradients.
然后你最终得到了多个局部渐变。
So, you can work out um,
所以，你可以解决这个问题，
the partial of Z with respect to X,
相对于X的Z的部分，
or the partial of Z with respect to W. And so,
或相对于W的Z的部分。所以，
you essentially you take the upstream gradient,
你基本上你采取上游梯度，
you multiply it by each of the local gradients,
你将它乘以每个局部渐变，
and you pass it down the respective path,
然后你把它传递到相应的路径上，
and we calculate these different downstream gradients to pass along.
我们计算这些不同的下游梯度来传递。
Is that making sense?
这有道理吗？
Yeah. Okay. How chug.
是啊。好的。怎么突然。
Okay. So, let's sort of look in an example of this and then we'll see one other case.
好的。所以，让我们看看这个例子，然后我们会看到另一个案例。
So here's the little baby example.
所以这是小宝贝的例子。
This isn't kind of really looking like a neural net,
这不像是神经网络，
but we've got three inputs x, y, and z.
但是我们有三个输入x，y和z。
And x and y get added together and y and z you get maxed.
并且x和y加在一起，y和z得到最大值。
And then we take the results of those two operations and we multiply them together.
然后我们将这两个操作的结果加在一起，然后将它们相乘。
So overall what we're calculating is x plus y times the max of y plus z.
总的来说，我们计算的是x加y乘以y加z的最大值。
But, you know, we have here a general technique and we can apply it in any cases.
但是，你知道，我们这里有一般技术，我们可以在任何情况下应用它。
Okay, so if we wanted to have this graph and we want to run it forward,
好的，所以如果我们想要这个图并且我们想要向前运行它，
well, we need to know the values of x, y, and z.
好吧，我们需要知道x，y和z的值。
So, for my example x equals one y equals two z equals zero.
所以，对于我的例子，x等于一个y等于两个z等于零。
Um, so, we take the values of those variables and
嗯，所以，我们采取这些变量的值和
push them onto the calculations for the forward arrows.
将它们推到前进箭头的计算上。
And then well the first thing we do is add and the result of that is three.
然后我们做的第一件事是添加，结果是三。
And so we can put that onto the arrow.
所以我们可以把它放在箭头上。
That's the output of add.
这是add的输出。
Max it's two as the output of the value of add times is six.
最大值为2，因为加时间值的输出为6。
And so the forward pass we have evaluated the expression.
所以我们已经对前向传递评估了表达式。
Its value is six.
它的价值是六。
That wasn't hard. Okay. So then the next step is we
那并不难。好的。那么下一步就是我们
then want to run back-propagation to work out gradients.
然后想要运行反向传播来计算渐变。
Um, and so we sort of want to know how to sort of,
嗯，所以我们想知道如何排序，
um work out these local gradients.
嗯解决这些局部渐变。
So a is our right a is the result of sum.
所以a是我们的权利a是和的结果。
So here's a as the result of sum.
所以这是总和的结果。
So a equals x plus y.
所以a等于x加y。
So if you're taking da dx that's just one and d a d y is also one that makes sense.
因此，如果你正在使用da dx那只是一个而dady也是有意义的。
Um, the max is slightly trickier because where
嗯，最大有点棘手，因为在哪里
there's some slopes and gradient for the max depends on which one's bigger.
有一些斜坡和最大的梯度取决于哪一个更大。
So, if y is bigger than z d- delta,
所以，如果y大于z d-delta，
the partial of b by z,
b的部分b，
plus partial b by y is one otherwise it's 0 and conversely for the partial of b by z.
+ y除了部分b，否则为0，相反，对于b的部分为z。
So that one's a little bit dependent.
所以一个人有点依赖。
And then we do the multiplication, um,
然后我们做乘法，嗯，
case at the end, um,
最后的情况，嗯，
and work out its partials with respect to a and b.
并针对a和b计算其部分内容。
And, um, since that's a and b which has the values two and three.
而且，嗯，因为那是a和b，其值为2和3。
If you're taking the partial of f by a it equals b which is two and vice versa.
如果你把f的一部分取为a等于b是2，反之亦然。
Okay. So that means we can work out the local gradients at each node.
好的。这意味着我们可以计算出每个节点的局部梯度。
And so then we want to use those to
所以我们想要用它们
calculate our gradients backwards and the back-propagation paths.
计算我们的向后梯度和反向传播路径。
So we start at the top.
所以我们从顶部开始。
The partial of f with respect to F is one.
关于F的f的部分是1。
Because if you move if you know by a tenth then you've moved the f by a tenth.
因为如果你知道十分之一就移动那么你已经将f移动了十分之一。
So that's a cancels out as one.
所以这是一个取消。
Okay. So then we want to pass backwards.
好的。那么我们想要倒退。
So, the first thing that we have is this sort of multiply node.
所以，我们首先拥有的是这种乘法节点。
And so we worked- we know its local gradients that partial of f by a is two,
所以我们工作 - 我们知道它的局部渐变，f的一部分是2，
and the partial of f by b is three.
而b的部分f是3。
And so we get those values.
所以我们得到了这些价值观。
So formally we're taking the local gradients
所以我们正式采用当地的渐变方式
multiplying them by the upstream gradients and getting our three and two.
将它们乘以上游梯度并得到我们的三和二。
And notice the fact that so effectively what happens is the values on the two arcs swaps.
并注意到这样一个事实，即两个弧交换的值是如此有效。
Um, and then we sort of continue back.
嗯，然后我们继续回来。
Okay. There's a max node.
好的。有一个最大节点。
So our upstream gradient is now three and then we want to multiply by the local gradient.
所以我们的上游梯度现在是3，然后我们想要乘以局部梯度。
And since the max of these two as two has a slope of one on this side.
并且由于这两个中的两个最大值在这一侧具有一个斜率。
So you get three,
所以你得到三个，
there's no gradient on this side and we get zero.
这边没有渐变，我们得到零。
And then we do the similar calculation on
然后我们进行类似的计算
the other side where we have local gradients of one.
另一边我们有一个局部渐变。
And so both of them come out of two And then the one other thing to do is we notice,
所以他们两个都是两个然后另外要做的事情是我们注意到，
well, wait a minute.
好吧，等一下。
There are two arcs that started from the y
从y开始有两个弧
both of which we've backed complicated some gradient on.
我们所支持的两个都是复杂的渐变。
And so what do we do about that.
那么我们该怎么办呢。
Um, what we do about that is we sum.
嗯，我们对此做的是我们总结。
So, the partial of f by x is to the partial of f by z is 0 that the
因此，f乘以x的部分是f的部分，其中z是0
partial of f by y is the sum of the two and five, right?
f的y部分是两个和五个的总和，对吧？
And so this isn't complete voodoo.
所以这不是完整的伏都教。
This is something that should make sense in terms of what gradients are, right?
对于什么样的渐变来说，这是有意义的，对吧？
So, that what we're saying,
那就是我们所说的，
is what we're calculating,
是我们正在计算的，
is if you wiggle x a little bit
如果你稍微摆动一下那就好了
how big an effect does that have on the outcome of the whole thing?
这会对整个事物的结果产生多大的影响？
And so, you know, we should be able to work this out.
所以，你知道，我们应该能够解决这个问题。
So, our x started offers one but let's suppose we wiggle it up a bit
所以，我们的x开始提供一个，但让我们假设我们稍微摆动它
and make it 1,1 well according to this output should change by about 0,2,
根据这个输出使其变好1,1应改变约0,2，
it should be magnified by two.
它应该被放大两倍。
And we should be able to work that out, right?
我们应该能够解决这个问题吧？
So it's then 1,1 plus two,
所以它是1,1加2，
so that's then 3,1.
那就是3,1。
And then we've got the two here that multiplies by it and it's 6,2.
然后我们在这里将两个乘以它并且它是6,2。
And lo and behold it went up by 0,2, right?
并且看到它上升了0,2，对吗？
So that seems correct.
所以这似乎是正确的。
And if we try and do the same for,
如果我们尝试做同样的事情，
well, let's do the z. It's easy.
好吧，让我们做z。这很简单。
So if we wiggle the z which had a value of zero by 0,1.
因此，如果我们将值为零的z摆动0,1。
This is 0,1.
这是0,1。
When we max if this is still two and
当我们最大，如果这仍然是两个和
so a calculated value doesn't change, it's still six.
所以计算值不会改变，它仍然是六。
So the gradient here is zero.
所以这里的梯度为零。
Wiggling this does nothing.
扭动这没有任何作用。
And then the final one is y.
然后最后一个是y。
So, it's starting off value as two.
所以，它的价值就是两个。
So, if we wiggle it a little and make it 2,1,
所以，如果我们稍稍摆动它并使其成为2,1，
our claim is that the results are change by about 0,5.
我们的主张是结果变化约0,5。
It should be multiplied by five times.
它应该乘以五倍。
So, if we make this 2,1 we then have 2,1 plus one and b 3,1.
所以，如果我们制作2,1，那么我们就有2,1加1和b 3,1。
When we get the max here would also be 2,1.
当我们得到最大值时，这里也是2,1。
And so we'd have 2,1 times 3,1.
所以我们有2,1倍3,1。
And that's too hard arithmetic for me to do in my head.
这对我来说太难了算法。
But if we take 2,1 times 3,1 it comes out to 6,51.
但是如果我们拿2,1倍3,1它就会达到6,51。
So, basically it's gone up by half.
所以，基本上它已经上升了一半。
We don't expect the answers to be exact of course, right?
我们不希望答案当然是准确的，对吗？
Because you know that's not the way calculus works, right?
因为你知道这不是微积分的工作方式，对吗？
[NOISE]. Where that it's showing that we're getting the gradients right.
[噪声]。它表明我们正在获得正确的渐变。
Okay. So this actually works.
好的。所以这确实有效。
So, what are the techniques that we need to know?
那么，我们需要了解哪些技术？
Um, so we've sort of already seen them all.
嗯，所以我们已经看到了所有这些。
So, you know, we discussed when there are multiple incoming arcs,
所以，你知道，我们讨论了有多个传入弧，
how he saw workout the different local derivatives.
他如何看待锻炼不同的本地衍生品。
The main other case that we need to know is if, um,
我们需要知道的另一个主要案例是，如果，嗯，
in the function computation there's a branch
在函数计算中有一个分支
outward the resultant something is used in multiple places.
向外产生的东西用于多个地方。
And so this was like the case here.
所以这就像这里的情况。
I mean, here this was an initial variable,
我的意思是，这是一个初始变量，
but you know, it could have been computed by something further back.
但是你知道，它本可以通过更进一步的东西来计算。
So, if this thing is used in multiple places and
所以，如果这个东西用在多个地方和
you have the computation going out in different ways.
你有不同的计算方式。
It's just this simple rule that when you do backpropagation
当你进行反向传播时，这就是这个简单的规则
backwards you sum the gradients that you get from the different output branches.
向后，您可以总结从不同输出分支获得的渐变。
Okay. So, if a equals X plus Y and while that's the one we showed you
好的。所以，如果a等于X加Y，那就是我们向你展示的那个
before that were doing this some operation to work out the total partial of f by y.
在此之前做了一些操作来计算出y的总分f。
Okay. And if you sort of think about it just a little bit more,
好的。如果你只是想一点点，
there's sort of these obvious patterns,
有这些明显的模式，
um, which we saw in this very simple example.
嗯，我们在这个非常简单的例子中看到过。
So, if you've got a plus that really the upstream gradient is going to
所以，如果你有一个加号，真的是上游渐变
be sort of heading down every one of
有点像每一个人
these grant branches when you have multiple branches are things being summed.
当你有多个分支时，这些授予分支是被总结的东西。
Now, in this case,
现在，在这种情况下，
it just as copied unchanged but that's because our computation was x plus y.
它只是复制不变，但那是因为我们的计算是x加y。
You know, it could be more complicated,
你知道，它可能会更复杂，
but we're passing it down down each of those branches.
但是我们将它们传递给每个分支机构。
So plus distributes upstream gradient.
所以加上分配上游梯度。
When you have a max that's kind of like a routing operation,
如果你有一个类似于路由操作的最大值，
because max is going to be sending the gradient to in the direction that's the max,
因为max会将渐变发送到最大的方向，
and other things are going to get no gradient being passed down to them.
和其他事情将没有梯度传递给他们。
Um, and then when you have, um,
嗯，然后当你有，嗯，
a multiplication this has this kind of
这是一种乘法
fun effect that what you do is switch the gradient, right?
你做的有趣的效果是切换渐变，对吗？
And so this reflects the fact that when you have u times
所以这反映了当你有你的时候
v regardless of whether u and v are vectors or just,
v无论你和v是向量还是只是，
um, scalars that the derivative of the result with respect to
嗯，标量表示结果的衍生物
u is v and the derivative of those spot- result with respect to v is u.
你是v，那些关于v的结果的衍生物是u。
And so, the, um,
那么，嗯，
gradient signal is the flip,
渐变信号是翻转，
um, of the tw- two numbers on the different sides.
嗯，不同方面的两个数字。
Okay. Um, so this is sort of most of how we have
好的。嗯，所以这就是我们的大部分时间
these computation graphs and we can work out backpropagation backwards in them.
这些计算图表我们可以在它们中向后计算反向传播。
There's sort of one more part of this to do,
还有一部分要做，
um, which is to say g,
嗯，也就是说g，
we want to do this eff- efficiently.
我们想要有效地做到这一点。
So, there's a bad way to do this which is to say, "Oh well,
所以，这样做的方法很糟糕，就是说，“哦，好吧，
we wanted to calculate the partial of this by b and so we can calculate that partial."
我们想用b来计算它的部分，所以我们可以计算出它的部分。“
Which was essentially what I was doing on last time slides.
这基本上就是我上次幻灯片时的做法。
We say, "Um, partial of s by b equals the partial of s by h,
我们说，“嗯，部分s由b等于s的部分h，
times the partial of h by z,
乘以z的部分h，
times the partial of z by b,
乘以b的部分z，
and we have all of those partials.
我们拥有所有这些部分内容。
We work them all out and multiply them together and then someone says,
我们全力以赴，将它们相乘，然后有人说，
um, what's the partial of s by w?
嗯，w的部分内容是什么？
And we say, huh, that's the chain rule again, I'll do it all again.
而且我们说，嗯，这又是连锁规则，我会再做一遍。
It's the partial of s by,
这是s的部分，
um, h times the partial of h by z,
嗯，h乘以z的部分h，
times the partial of and z by x,
乘以x的部分和z，
no, no, right, ah, lost it.
不，不，对，啊，失去了它。
But you do big long list of them and you calculate all again.
但你做了很长的清单，然后再计算一遍。
That's not what we want to do.
那不是我们想要做的。
Instead we want to say, "Oh,
相反，我们想说，“哦，
look there's this shared stuff.
看看这是共享的东西。
There's this error signal coming from above."
这个错误信号来自上方。“
And we can work out the error signal the upstream gradient for this node.
我们可以计算出该节点上游梯度的误差信号。
We can use it to calculate the upstream gradient for this node.
我们可以用它来计算这个节点的上游梯度。
We can use this to calculate the upstream gradient for this node and then,
我们可以用它来计算这个节点的上游梯度然后，
using the local gradients of which there are two calculated
使用局部梯度，其中有两个计算
this node we can then calculate this one and that one.
然后我们可以计算这个节点和那个节点。
Um, and then, from here having knowing this upstream gradient,
嗯，然后，从这里知道这个上游梯度，
we can use the local gradients at this node to compute this one and that one.
我们可以使用此节点上的局部渐变来计算这个和那个。
And so, we're sort of doing this efficient computer science like computation,
所以，我们有点像计算这样有效的计算机科学，
um, where we don't do any repeated work. That makes sense?
嗯，我们不做任何重复工作。那讲得通？
Yeah. Okay. Um, and so if that is,
是啊。好的。嗯，如果那样的话，
um, the whole of backprop.
嗯，整个反推。
So, um, here's sort of a slightly sketchy um graph
所以，嗯，这里有点粗略的um图
which is sort of just re-capitulating this thing.
这有点只是重新投降这件事。
So, if you have any computation that you want to perform, um, well,
所以，如果你有任何你想要执行的计算，嗯，嗯，
the hope is that you can sort your nodes into
希望您可以将节点排序为
what's called a topological sort which means that things that are arguments,
什么称为拓扑排序，这意味着作为参数的东西，
variables that are arguments are sorted before
作为参数的变量之前是排序的
variables that are results that depend on that argument.
变量是依赖于该参数的结果。
You know, providing you have something there's an a cyclic graph,
你知道，如果你有东西有一个循环图，
you'll be able to do that.
你将能够做到这一点。
If you have a cyclic graph, you're in trouble.
如果你有一个循环图，那你就麻烦了。
Um, well, I'd be there actually techniques people
嗯，好吧，我实际上是技术人员
use to roll out those graphs but I'm not gonna go into that now.
用来推出那些图表，但我现在不打算这样做。
So, we've sorted the nodes which is kind of loosely represented here from
所以，我们已经对这里松散表示的节点进行了排序
bottom to top in a topological sort area, sort.
在拓扑排序区域中从下到上排序。
Okay. So then, for the forward prop we sort of go through the nodes in
好的。那么，对于前向道具，我们会通过其中的节点
the topological sort order and we
拓扑排序顺序和我们
if it's a variable we just set its value to what it's favorite val- variable value is.
如果它是一个变量，我们只需将其值设置为它最喜欢的val变量值。
If it's computed from other variables their values must have been
如果它是从其他变量计算出来的，那么它们的值必须是
set already because there earlier in the topological sort, um,
因为在早期的拓扑排序中已经设置了，嗯，
and then we compute the value of those nodes according to their predecessors,
然后我们根据它们的前辈计算这些节点的值，
and we pass it up and work out the final output,
我们把它传递出来并计算最终输出，
the loss function of our neural network and that is our forward pass.
我们的神经网络的损失函数，这是我们的前进通道。
Okay. So then, after that we do our backward pass and so for
好的。那么，之后，我们做了向后传球，所以
the backward pass we initialize the output gradient with one.
向后传递我们用一个初始化输出梯度。
The top thing is always one,
最重要的是一个，
the partial of z with respect to z.
相对于z的z的部分。
And then, we now sort of go through the nodes in reverse topological sort.
然后，我们现在以反向拓扑排序方式遍历节点。
And so therefore, each of them will all ready- anything that's,
因此，他们每个人都准备好了 - 任何事情，
ah, anything that's, uh, language is complex.
啊，什么，呃，语言很复杂。
Anything that's above that.
任何高于此的东西。
Anything that we calculated based on it in terms of, ah,
我们根据它计算的任何东西啊，
forward pass will already have had calculated it's, um,
前进已经计算好了，嗯，
it's gradient as a product of upstream gradient
它是梯度作为上游梯度的产物
times local gradient and then we can use that,
乘以局部渐变然后我们可以使用它，
um, to compute the next thing down.
嗯，计算下一件事。
Um, and so basically the ov- the overall role
嗯，基本上是ov-整体角色
is for any node you work out its set of successors,
适用于任何节点，你可以计算出它的后继者，
the things that are above it that it,
它上面的东西，
that depend on it and then you say, "Okay,
取决于它，然后你说，“好的，
the partial of z with respect to x is simply the sum over the set of
相对于x的z的部分简单地是该组的总和
successors of the local gradient that you
你所在的局部渐变的继承者
calculated the node times the upstream gradient of that node."
计算节点乘以该节点的上游梯度。“
Um, and in the examples that I gave before there was never,
嗯，在我从未给过的例子中，
never multiple upstream gradients.
永远不会有多个上游梯度。
But if you imagine a, a general big graph there could actually be
但是如果你想象一个普通的大图可能会有
so different upstream gradients that are being used in- for the various successors.
如此不同的上游梯度，用于各种后继者。
So, we apply that backwards and then we've worked out in backpropagation, um,
那么，我们向后应用，然后我们已经在反向传播，嗯，
the gradient of every,
每一个的梯度，
the gradient of the final result z with respect to every node in our graph.
关于图中每个节点的最终结果z的梯度。
Um, and the thing to notice about this is,
嗯，关于这个的事情是，
if you're doing it right and efficiently,
如果你正确而有效地做到了
the bigger o order of complexity of doing backpropagation is exactly the
进行反向传播的复杂程度正好相反
same as doing forward propagation i.e expression evaluation.
与前向传播相同，即表达评估。
So, it's not some super expensive complex procedure
所以，这不是一些超级昂贵的复杂程序
that you can imagine doing and scaling up.
你可以想象做和扩大规模。
Um, you're actually in exactly the same complexity order.
嗯，你实际上处于完全相同的复杂性顺序。
Okay. Um, so as [inaudible] entered it here this procedure,
好的。嗯，所以[音频不清晰]在这里输入了这个程序，
you could just think of something that you're running on
你可以想到你正在运行的东西
an arbitrary graph and calculating this forward pass and the backwards pass.
任意图形并计算此向前传递和向后传递。
I mean, almost without exception that the kind of
我的意思是，几乎无一例外的那种
neural nets that we actually use have a regular layer
我们实际使用的神经网络有一个常规层
like structure and that's then precisely why it makes
就像结构一样，那就是它的原因
to- sense to work out these gradients in terms of,
感觉到这些渐变的方法，
um, vectors matrices and Jacobian's as the kind we were before.
嗯，矢量矩阵和Jacobian's就像我们以前那样。
Okay. Um, so since we have this sort of really nice algorithm now, um,
好的。嗯，既然我们现在有这种非常好的算法，嗯，
this sort of means that, um,
这意味着，嗯，
we can do this just computationally and so we don't have to think or know how to do math.
我们可以通过计算方式完成这项工作，因此我们不必考虑或知道如何进行数学运算。
Um, and we can just have our computers do all of this with this.
嗯，我们可以让我们的计算机完成这一切。
Um, so that using this graph structure, um,
嗯，所以使用这个图形结构，嗯，
we can just automatically work out how to apply, um, backprop.
我们可以自动解决如何应用，嗯，backprop。
And there are sort of two cases of this, right?
有两种情况，对吗？
So, if what was calculated at each node,
那么，如果在每个节点计算了什么，
um, is given as a symbolic expression,
嗯，是一个象征性的表达，
we could actually have our computer work out for
我们实际上可以让我们的计算机工作
us what the derivative of that symbolic expression is.
我们这个象征性表达的衍生物是什么。
So, it could actually calculate, um,
所以，它实际上可以计算，嗯，
the gradient of that node and that's referred to as often as automatic differentiation.
该节点的梯度，通常称为自动微分。
So, this is kind of like Mathematica Wolfram Alpha.
所以，这有点像Mathematica Wolfram Alpha。
You know how you can do your math homework on it?
你知道怎么做数学作业吗？
You just type in your expression,
你只需输入你的表达，
say what's a derivative and it gives it back to you right?
说什么是衍生品，它给你回报了吗？
Um, it's working doing symbolic computation and working out the derivative for you.
嗯，它正在进行符号计算并为你计算衍生物。
Um, so that- so that method could be used to
嗯，所以 - 这样的方法可以用来
work out the local gradients and then we can use
找出当地的渐变，然后我们就可以使用了
the graph structure and now rule
图形结构和现在的规则
upstream gradient times local gradient gives downstream gradient,
上游梯度时间局部梯度给出下游梯度，
i.e the chain rule, um,
即链条规则，嗯，
to then propagate it through the graph and do
然后通过图表传播它并做
the whole backward pass completely automatically.
整个向后传递完全自动。
And so that sounds, um, great.
所以听起来，嗯，很棒。
Um, slight disappointment, um,
嗯，有点失望，嗯，
current deep learning frameworks don't quite give you that.
目前的深度学习框架并没有给你那么多。
Um, there was actually a famous framework that attempted to give you that.
嗯，实际上有一个着名的框架试图给你这个。
So the Theano Framework that was developed at the University of Montreal, um,
所以在蒙特利尔大学开发的Theano框架，嗯，
those they've now abandoned in the modern era
那些他们现在已经放弃在现代的人
of large technology corporation, deep learning frameworks.
大型科技公司，深度学习框架。
Theano did precisely that.
Theano正是这样做的。
It did the full thing of automatic differentiation, um,
它做了自动分化的全部功能，嗯，
for reasons that we could either think of good or bad,
由于我们可能想到好或坏的原因，
current deep learning frameworks like TensorFlow or
目前的深度学习框架，如TensorFlow或
PyTorch actually do a little bit less than that.
PyTorch实际上做的比这少一点。
So what they do is, say,
所以，他们所做的就是说，
well for an indiv- for the computations at an individual node,
适用于个别节点的计算，
you have to do the calculus for yourself.
你必须为自己做微积分。
Um, for this individual node,
嗯，对于这个单独的节点，
you have to write the forward propagation, say, you know,
你必须写前向传播，比方说，你知道，
return X plus Y and you have to write the backward propagation,
返回X加Y，你必须写反向传播，
saying the local gradients, uh,
说当地的渐变，呃，
one and one to the two inputs X and Y, um,
一个和一个到两个输入X和Y，嗯，
but providing you or someone else has
但是为你或其他人提供
written out the forward and backward local step at this node,
写出这个节点的前后本地步骤，
then TensorFlow or PyTorch does all the rest
然后TensorFlow或PyTorch完成剩下的工作
of it for you and runs the backpropagation algorithm.
对你来说并运行反向传播算法。
[NOISE] Um, and then, you know, effectively,
[NOISE]嗯，然后，你知道，有效，
that sort of saves you having to have a big symbolic computation engine,
那种节省你必须有一个大的符号计算引擎，
because somewhat, the person coding
因为有些人，编码的人
the node computations is writing
节点计算正在写入
a bit of code as you might normally imagine doing it whether in,
一些代码，正如你通常想象的那样，无论是否在
you know, C or Pascal,
你知道吗，C或Pascal，
of saying returning X plus Y,
说返回X加Y，
and, you know, local Gradient return one.
而且，你知道，当地的Gradient会返回一个。
Right? And- and you don't actually have to have a whole symbolic computation engine.
对？并且 - 你实际上不必拥有一个完整的符号计算引擎。
Okay. So that means the overall picture looks like this.
好的。这意味着整体情况看起来像这样。
Right? So um, schematically,
对？嗯，示意，
we have a computation graph, um,
我们有一个计算图，嗯，
and to calculate the forward computation, um,
并计算正向计算，嗯，
we, um, so- sort of put inputs into
我们，嗯，所以 - 投入
our computation graph where there's sort of X and Y variables,
我们的计算图，其中有一些X和Y变量，
and then we run through the nodes in topologically sorted order,
然后我们以拓扑排序的顺序遍历节点，
and for each node we calculate its forward and
对于每个节点，我们计算它的前向和
necessarily the things that depends on and have already been
必然是依赖和已经存在的事物
computed and we just do expression evaluation forward.
计算，我们只是向前进行表达式评估。
And then we return, um,
然后我们回来，嗯，
the final gate in the graph,
图中的最后一道门，
which is our loss function, or objective function.
这是我们的损失函数或目标函数。
But then, also we have the backward pass,
但是，我们也有向后传球，
and for the backward pass,
而对于向后传球，
we go in the nodes in reversed topological, um, resorted order,
我们进入逆向拓扑，嗯，求助顺序的节点，
and for each of those nodes,
并为每个节点，
we've return their backward value,
我们已经回归了它们的价值，
and for their top node,
对于他们的顶级节点，
we return backward value of one,
我们返回一个的后向值，
and that will then give us our gradients.
那将会给我们提供渐变。
And so that means, um,
所以这意味着，嗯，
for any node, any piece of computation that we perform,
对于任何节点，我们执行的任何计算，
we need to write a little bit of code that um
我们需要写一些代码来嗯
says what it's doing on the forward pass and what it's doing on the backward pass.
说它在前锋传球上做了什么，以及它在后场传球上做了什么。
So on the forward pass, um,
所以在前进传球上，嗯，
this is our multiplication,
这是我们的倍增，
so we're just saying return X times Y.
所以我们只是说回归X倍Y.
So that's pretty easy.
所以这很容易。
That's what you're used to doing.
这就是你们习惯做的事情。
But while we also need to do the backward passes,
但是我们还需要做后退传球，
local gradients of return what is the
当地的渐变回归是什么
partial of L with respect to Z and with respect to X.
相对于Z和相对于X的部分L.
And well, to do that,
好吧，要做到这一点，
we have to do a little bit more work.
我们要做更多的工作。
So we have to do a little bit more work,
所以我们要做更多的工作，
first of all, in the forward pass.
首先，在前锋传球。
So, in the forward pass,
所以，在前进传球中，
we have to remember to sort of stuff away in some variables
我们必须记住一些变量中的东西
what values we computed in the for-
我们在for-中计算了什么值
what- what values were given to us in the forward pass,
什么 - 前进传球给了我们什么价值，
or else we won't be able to calculate the backward pass.
否则我们将无法计算后向传球。
So we store away the values of X and Y,
所以我们存储了X和Y的值，
um, and so then,
嗯，等等，
when we're doing the backward pass,
当我们做后退时，
we are passed into us the upstream Gradient,
我们将上游Gradient传递给我们
the error signal, and now we just do calculate, um,
错误信号，现在我们只是计算，嗯，
upstream Gradient times local Gradient- upstream Gradient times local Gradient,
上游梯度时间局部梯度 - 上游梯度乘以局部梯度，
and we return backwards,
我们向后退，
um, those um downstream Gradients.
嗯，那些下游的Gradients。
And so providing we do that for all the nodes of our graph,
因此，我们为图表的所有节点提供此功能，
um, we then have something that, um,
嗯，我们有一些东西，嗯，
the system can learn for us as a deep learning system.
系统可以为我们学习深度学习系统。
And so what that means in practice,
那么这在实践中意味着什么，
um, is that, you know,
嗯，是的，你知道，
any of these deep learning frameworks come with a whole box of tools that says,
这些深度学习框架中的任何一个都附带了一整套工具，
um, here is a fully connected forward layer,
嗯，这是一个完全连接的前向层，
here is a sigmoid unit,
这是一个sigmoid单位，
here is other more complicated things we'll do later,
这是我们稍后会做的其他更复杂的事情，
like convolutions and recurrent layers.
像卷积和复发层。
And to the extent that you are using one of those,
并且就你使用其中一个而言，
somebody else has done this work for you.
别人为你做了这项工作。
Right? That they've um defined, um,
对？那是他们定义的，嗯，
nodes or a layer of nodes that have forward and backward already written for- for them.
节点或已经为其编写前向和后向的节点层。
And to the extent that that's true, um,
在某种程度上，这是真的，嗯，
that means that making neural nets is heaps of fun. It's just like lego.
这意味着制作神经网络是一大堆乐趣。就像乐高一样。
Right? You just stick these layers together and say,
对？你只需将这些层粘在一起然后说，
"God, I have to learn on some data and train it."
“上帝，我必须学习一些数据并进行训练。”
You know, it's so easy that my high school student is building these things.
你知道，我的高中生正在建造这些东西这么容易。
Right? Um, you don't have to understand much really,
对？嗯，你真的不需要了解，
um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
to the extent that you actually want to do some original research and think,
在某种程度上，你真的想做一些原创研究和思考，
"I've got this really cool idea of how to do things differently.
“我对如何以不同的方式做事真的很酷。
I'm going to define my own kind of different computation."
我要定义自己的不同计算方法。“
Well, then you have to do this and define your class,
那么，你必须这样做并定义你的班级，
and as well as, sort of saying,
而且，有点说，
how to compute the forward value,
如何计算前向值，
you will have to pull out your copy of
你必须拿出你的副本
Wolfram Alpha and work out what the derivatives are,
Wolfram Alpha并弄清楚衍生品是什么，
um, and put that into the backward pass.
嗯，把它放到后面的通道里。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
Okay. So here's just one little more note on that.
好的。所以这里只是一点点注意事项。
Um, you know, in the early days of deep learning,
嗯，你知道，在深度学习的早期，
say prior to 2014,
在2014年之前说，
what we always used to state to everybody very sternly is,
我们总是非常严厉地向每个人陈述的是，
"You should check all your Gradients,
“你应该检查所有的渐变，
by doing numeric Gradient checks.
通过数字梯度检查。
It's really really important."
这真的非常重要。“
Um, and so what that meant was, well, you know,
嗯，那是什么意思，嗯，你知道，
if you want to know whether you have coded your backward pass right,
如果你想知道你是否已经对你的后向传球进行了编码，
an easy way to check, um,
一个简单的方法来检查，嗯，
whether you've coded it right,
你是否编码正确，
is to do this numeric Gradient
是做这个数字渐变
where you're sort of estimating the slope by wiggling it a bit,
通过摆动它来估计斜率的方式，
and wiggling the input a bit,
并稍微摆动输入，
and seeing what effect it has.
并看看它有什么影响。
So I'm working out the value of the function the F of X plus H,
所以我正在研究X加H的函数值，
for H very small like E to the minus four,
因为H很小，比如E到负四，
and then F of X minus H, um,
然后是X的减去H，嗯，
and then dividing by 2H,
然后除以2H，
and I'm saying well, what is the slope at this point,
我说得很好，此时的坡度是多少，
and I'm getting a numeric estimate of the Gradient with respect,
而且我得到了Gradient的数值估计值，
um, to my variable X here.
嗯，这里给我的变量X.
Um, so this is what you will have seen in
嗯，这就是你将要看到的
high school when you did the sort of first um estimates of Gradients,
高中的时候你做过第一次对渐变的估计，
where you sort of worked out F of X plus H divided by H
你在哪里计算出X加H除以H的F
and you're doing rise over run and got a point estimate of the Gradient.
并且你正在超越跑步并且得到了渐变的点估计。
Um, exactly the same thing,
嗯，完全一样的，
except for the fact,
除了事实，
in this case, rather than doing it one sided like that,
在这种情况下，而不是像这样单方面，
we are doing it two-sided.
我们这样做是双面的。
It turns out that if you actually wanna do this,
事实证明，如果你真的想这样做，
two-sided is asymptotically hugely [NOISE] better,
双面渐近巨大[NOISE]更好，
and so you're always better off doing
所以你总是做得更好
two-sided Gradient checks rather than one-sided Gradient checks.
双向渐变检查而不是单侧渐变检查。
Um, so since you saw that- since it's hard to implement this wrong,
嗯，所以既然你看到了 - 因为很难实现这个错误，
this is a good way to check that your Gradients are
这是检查Gradients的好方法
correct if you've defined them yourselves.
如果你自己定义了它们就更正了。
Um, as a technique to use it [NOISE] for anything,
嗯，作为一种使用它[NOISE]的技术，
it's completely, completely hopeless,
这完全是完全没有希望的
because we're thinking of doing this over
因为我们正在考虑这样做
our deep learning model for a fully connected layer.
我们的完全连接层的深度学习模型。
What this means [NOISE] is that,
这意味着[NOISE]是什么意思，
if you've got this sort of like a W matrix of N by M and you want to, um,
如果你有这样的W矩阵N乘以M你想要，嗯，
calculate um your partial derivatives to check if they're correct,
计算你的偏导数以检查它们是否正确，
it means that you have to do this for every element of the matrix.
这意味着您必须为矩阵的每个元素执行此操作。
So you have to calculate the eventual loss,
所以你必须计算最终的损失，
first jiggling W11, then jiggling W12,
先摇晃W11，然后摇晃W12，
then jiggling one- W13, 14 et cetera.
然后摇晃一个W13,14等等。
So you have- in the complex network,
所以你在复杂的网络中
you'll end up literally doing millions of function evaluations
你最终将完成数以百万计的功能评估
to check the Gradients at one point in time.
在某个时间点检查渐变。
So, you know, it's,
所以，你知道，是的，
it's not like what I advertised for
它不像我所宣传的那样
backprop when I said it's just as efficient as calculating,
backprop当我说它和计算一样有效时，
um, the forward value.
嗯，前瞻性的价值。
Doing this is forward
这样做是向前的
value computation time multiplied by number of parameters in our model,
值计算时间乘以模型中的参数数量，
which is often huge for deep learning networks.
这对于深度学习网络来说通常是巨大的。
So this is something that you only want to
所以这是你唯一想要的
have inside- if statements that you could turn off.
有内部 - 如果声明你可以关闭。
So you could just sort of run it to check that your code isn't bre- um, debuggy.
所以你可以运行它来检查你的代码是不是很严重，调试。
Um, you know, in honesty,
嗯，你知道，诚实，
this is just much less needed now because, you know,
这只是现在不太需要了，因为，你知道，
by and large you can plug together your components and layers and PyTorch,
总的来说，你可以将你的组件和层与PyTorch连接在一起，
um, and other people wrote the code right and it will work.
嗯，其他人写的代码是正确的，它会工作。
Um, so you probably don't need to do this all the time.
嗯，所以你可能不需要一直这样做。
But it is still a useful thing to look at and to know
但是，查看和了解它仍然是一件有用的事情
about if things um, are going wrong.
如果事情呃，那就错了。
Yeah. Okay, so we- we've now mastered the core technology of neural nets.
是啊。好的，我们 - 我们现在已经掌握了神经网络的核心技术。
We saw now well, basically everything we need to know about neural nets,
我们现在看得很清楚，基本上我们需要了解神经网络的一切，
and I sort of just, um, summarized it there.
而我有点，嗯，在那里总结一下。
Um, just to sort of emphasize um once more.
嗯，只是再次强调一下。
Um, you know, I think some people think,
嗯，你知道，我觉得有些人认为，
why do we even lear- need to learn all this stuff about gradients?'
为什么我们甚至学习 - 需要学习关于渐变的所有这些东西？
And there's a sense in which it's [inaudible] really,
并且有一种感觉，它[听不清]真的，
because these modern deep learning frameworks will compute all of the gradients for you.
因为这些现代深度学习框架将为您计算所有渐变。
You know, we make you suffer on homework two,
你知道，我们让你在家庭作业上受苦两个，
but in homework three,
但在作业三，
you can have your gradients computed for you.
你可以为你计算你的渐变。
But, you know, I- so you know it's sort of just, like, well,
但是，你知道，我 - 所以你知道它有点像，好吧，
why should you take a c- a class on compilers, right?
为什么要对编译器进行c-a课，对吧？
That there's actually something useful in understanding what goes on under the hood,
实际上，在了解引擎盖下发生的事情时，实际上有一些有用的东西，
even though most of the time,
即使大部分时间，
we're just perfectly happy to let the C compiler do its thing,
我们非常高兴让C编译器做到这一点，
without being experts on X86 assembler every day of the wa- week.
在这周的每一天都没有成为X86汇编程序的专家。
But, you know, there is more to it than that.
但是，你知道，还有更多的东西。
Um, you know, because even though backpropagation is great,
嗯，你知道，因为即使反向传播很棒，
once you're building complex models,
一旦你建造复杂的模型，
backpropagation doesn't always work as you would expect it to.
反向传播并不总是像你期望的那样工作。
Perfectly is maybe the wrong word,
完全可能是错误的词，
because you know mathematically it's perfect.
因为你在数学上知道它是完美的。
Um, but it might not be achieving what you're wanting it to.
嗯，但它可能没有实现你想要它。
And well, if you want to sort of then debug an improved models,
好吧，如果你想要调试一个改进的模型，
it's kind of crucial to understand what's going on.
理解正在发生的事情是至关重要的。
So, there's a nice medium piece by Andre Karpathy,
所以，Andre Karpathy有一个很好的媒体作品，
of yes you should understand backprop um that's on the syllabus page, um,
是的你应该理解backprop嗯那是在教学大纲页面上，嗯，
that talks about this and indeed um, um,
谈到这个，实际上，嗯，嗯，
week after next, Abby is actually going to lecture about recurrent neural networks,
接下来的一周，艾比实际上将要讲述关于复发神经网络，
and you know one of the places, um,
你知道其中一个地方，嗯，
where you can easily fail um,
你容易失败的地方，
and doing backpropagation turns up there,
然后做反向传播
um, is a good example.
嗯，是一个很好的例子。
Okay. So anyone have any questions about backpropagation and computation graphs?
好的。那么任何人对反向传播和计算图有什么疑问？
Okay. If not the remainder of the time is, um,
好的。如果不是剩余的时间，嗯，
the grab bag of things that you really should know about,
抓住你真正应该知道的东西，
if you're going to be doing deep learning.
如果你要做深度学习。
And so, yeah, this is just itsy-bitsy and,
所以，是的，这只是它的一点点，而且，
but let me say them.
但是让我说出来。
Um, so up until now,
嗯，直到现在，
when we've had um loss functions,
当我们有失去功能的时候，
and we've been maximizing the likelihood of our data,
我们一直在最大限度地提高数据的可能性，
and stuff like that,
和那样的东西，
we've sort of just had this part here which is the likelihood of our data,
我们在这里只是有这个部分，这是我们数据的可能性，
and we've worked to maximize it.
我们努力使它最大化。
Um, however, um, in practice that works badly usually,
嗯，嗯，在实践中通常很糟糕，
and we need to do something else which is regularize our models.
我们需要做一些其他事情来规范我们的模型。
And if you've done the Machine Learning class,
如果你已经完成了机器学习课程，
or something like that you will have seen regularization.
或类似的东西，你会看到正规化。
And there are various techniques to do regularization, but, um,
并且有各种技术可以进行正规化，但是，嗯，
compared to anything else,
与其他任何东西相比，
regularization is even more important,
正规化更为重要，
um, for deep learning models, right?
嗯，对于深度学习模型，对吧？
So, um, the general idea is if you have a lot of parameters in your model,
所以，嗯，一般的想法是你的模型中有很多参数，
those parameters can just essentially memorize what's in the data that you trained at.
这些参数可以基本上记住您训练的数据中的内容。
And so they're very good at predicting the answers.
所以他们非常擅长预测答案。
The model becomes very good at predicting the answers to the data you trained it on,
该模型非常擅长预测您训练的数据的答案，
but the model may become poor at working in the real world, and different examples.
但是在现实世界中工作的模型可能变得很差，而且不同的例子。
And somehow we want to stop that.
不知怎的，我们想要阻止它。
And this problem is especially bad for deep learning models,
这个问题对深度学习模型尤其不利，
because typically deep learning models have vast,
因为通常深度学习模型很广泛，
vast numbers of parameters.
大量的参数。
So in the good old days when statisticians ruled the show,
因此，在统计学家统治展览的过去，
they told people that it was completely ridiculous to
他们告诉人们，这完全是荒谬的
have a number of parameters that approached your number of training examples.
有许多参数接近你的训练样例数。
You know, you should never have more parameters in your model,
你知道，你的模型中不应该有更多的参数，
than one-tenth of the number of your training examples.
超过训练样例数的十分之一。
So it's the kind of um rules of thumb you are told,
所以这是你被告知的那种经验法则，
so that you had lots of examples with which to estimate every parameter.
所以你有很多例子来估计每个参数。
Um, that's just not true with deep learning models,
嗯，深度学习模型不行，
is just really common that we trained
我们训练得非常普遍
deep learning models that have 10 times as many parameters,
深度学习模型的参数是参数的10倍，
as we have training examples.
因为我们有训练的例子。
Um, but miraculously it works.
嗯，但奇迹般地有效。
In fact it works brilliantly.
事实上，它的工作非常出色。
Those highly over parameterized models,
那些高度参数化的模型，
and this one of the big secret sources of why deep learning has been so brilliant,
这是为什么深度学习如此辉煌的重要秘密来源之一，
but it only works if we regularize the model.
但它只有在我们规范模型时才有效。
So, if you train a model without sufficient regularization,
所以，如果你训练的模型没有足够的正则化，
what you find is that you're training it and working out your loss on the training data,
你发现的是你正在训练它并计算你在训练数据上的损失，
and the model keeps on getting better,
而且模型不断变好，
and better, and better, and better.
更好，更好，更好。
Um, necessarily, alg- algorithm has to improve loss on the training data.
嗯，必然，算法必须改善训练数据的损失。
So the worst thing that could happen,
所以可能发生的最糟糕的事情，
is that the graph could become absolutely fa- flat.
是图表可能变得绝对平淡。
What you'll find is with most models that we train,
您会发现我们训练的大多数模型，
they have so many parameters that this will just keep on going down,
他们有这么多参数，这将继续下去，
until the loss is sort of approaching the numerical precision of zero,
直到损失接近零的数值精度，
if you leave it training for long enough.
如果你留下足够长的训练时间。
It just learns the correct answer for every example,
它只是为每个例子都学会了正确的答案，
beca- because effectively can memorize the examples.
因为有效地可以记住这些例子。
Okay, but if you then say,
好的，但如果你说，
''Let me test out this model on some different data.''
“让我在一些不同的数据上测试这个模型。”
What you find is this red curve,
你发现的是这条红色曲线，
that up until a certain point, um,
直到某一点，嗯，
that you are also building a model that's better at predicting on different data,
您还在构建一个更好地预测不同数据的模型，
but after some point this curve starts to curve up again.
但经过一段时间后，这条曲线又开始向上弯曲。
And ignore that bit where it seems to curve down again,
并忽略它似乎再次弯曲的位，
that was a mistake in the drawing.
这是绘图中的一个错误。
Um, and so this is then referred to as over-fitting,
嗯，所以这被称为过度拟合，
that the- from here on the training model is
从这里开始训练模型
just learning to memorize whatever was in the training data,
只是学会记住训练数据中的任何内容，
but not in a way that later generalized to other examples.
但不是后来推广到其他例子的方式。
And so this is not what we want.
所以这不是我们想要的。
We want to try and avoid over-fitting as much as possible,
我们想尽量避免过度贴合，
and there are various regularization techniques that we use for that.
我们使用各种正规化技术。
And simple starting one is this one here where we penalize the log-likelihood by saying,
简单的启动就是这里，我们通过说，惩罚对数可能性，
''You're going to be penalized to the extent that you move parameters away from zero.''
“如果你将参数从零开始移动，你就会受到惩罚。”
So the default state of nature is all parameters are zeros,
所以默认的自然状态是所有参数都是零，
so they're ignored on computations.
所以他们在计算上被忽略了。
You can have parameters that have big values,
您可以使用具有较大值的参数，
but you'll pee penalized a bit four,
但你会小便四点，
and this is referred to as L-2 regularization.
这被称为L-2正则化。
And, you know, that's sort of a starting point of
而且，你知道，这是一个起点
something sensible you could do with regularization,
正规化你可以做些明智的事，
but there's more to say later.
但是后来还有更多要说的。
And we'll talk in this sort of lecture before we discuss
在我们讨论之前，我们将在这种讲座中进行讨论
final projects of other clever regularization techniques at neural networks.
神经网络中其他聪明正则化技术的最终项目。
Okay. Um, grab bag number two,
好的。嗯，二号抓包，
vectorization is the term that you have here,
矢量化是你在这里的术语，
um, but it's not only vectors.
嗯，但它不仅仅是矢量。
This is also matrixization,
这也是矩阵化，
and higher dimensional matrices what are called tensors,
和更高维的矩阵，称为张量，
in this field tensorization.
在这个领域张力化。
Um, getting deep learning systems to run fast and
嗯，让深度学习系统快速运行
efficiently is only possible if we vectorize things.
只有在我们对事物进行矢量化时才有效。
Um, and what does that mean?
嗯，那是什么意思？
What that means is, you know,
这意味着，你知道，
the straightforward way to write a lot of code um,
编写大量代码的简单方法嗯，
that you saw in your first CS class,
你在第一个CS课上看到的，
is you say for I in range in um calculate random randi-1.
你是说我的范围在你计算随机randi-1。
Um, but when we want to be clever,
嗯，但是当我们想要聪明的时候，
um, people, um, that are doing things fast,
嗯，人们，嗯，快做事，
um, we say rather than work out this W dot one word vector at a time,
嗯，我们说的不是一次解决这个W点一个单词的向量，
and do it in a four loop,
并在四个循环中完成，
we could instead put all of our word vectors into one matrix,
我们可以把所有的单词向量放到一个矩阵中，
and then do simply one matrix-matrix multiply of W by our word vector matrix.
然后通过我们的单词向量矩阵简单地做一个W矩阵矩阵乘法。
And even if you run your code on your laptop on a CPU,
即使你在CPU上的笔记本电脑上运行你的代码，
you will find out that if you do it the vectorized way,
你会发现，如果你这样做的矢量化方式，
things will become hugely faster.
事情会变得非常快。
So in this example,
所以在这个例子中，
it became over an order of magnitude faster,
它变得快了一个数量级，
when doing it with a vector- vectorized rather than,
当使用矢量矢量化而不是，
um, with a full loop.
嗯，有一个完整的循环。
Um, and those gains are only compounded when we run code on a GPU,
嗯，当我们在GPU上运行代码时，这些收益才会复杂化，
that you'll get no gains and speed of tall on a GPU,
你不会在GPU上获得高效和高速，
unless your code is vectorized.
除非您的代码是矢量化的。
But if it is vectorized,
但如果它是矢量化的，
then you can hope to have results, of oh,
哦，你可以希望有结果哦，
yeah, this runs 40 times faster,
是的，运行速度快了40倍
than it did on the CPU.
而不是在CPU上。
Okay, um, yeah, so always try to use vectors and matrices not for loops.
好的，嗯，是的，所以总是尝试使用矢量和矩阵而不是循环。
Um, of course it's useful when developing stuff to time your code,
嗯，当然在开发代码时间时很有用，
and find out what's slow.
并找出什么是缓慢的。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
Point three.
第三点。
Um, okay, so we discussed this idea, um, last time,
嗯，好的，所以我们讨论了这个想法，嗯，上次，
and the time before that after- after having the sort of affine layer,
以及之后的那段时间之后 - 在有了那种仿射层之后，
where we took, you know,
我们在哪里，你知道，
go from X to WX, plus B.
从X到WX，加上B.
That's referred to as an affine layer,
这被称为仿射层，
so we're doing this, um,
所以我们这样做，嗯，
multiplying a vector by a matrice- matrix,
将矢量乘以矩阵矩阵，
and adding um biases.
并添加偏见。
We necessarily to have power and a deep network, um,
我们必须拥有权力和深层网络，嗯，
have to have some form of non-linearity.
必须有某种形式的非线性。
And so, I just wanted to go through a bit of background
所以，我只是想通过一些背景知识
on non-linearity is in what people use,
关于非线性是人们使用的，
and what to use.
以及使用什么。
So, if you're sort of starting from the idea of what we know is logistic regression, um,
所以，如果你从我们所知道的逻辑回归的想法开始，嗯，
what's commonly referred to as the sigmoid curve,
什么通常被称为S形曲线，
or maybe more precisely is the logistic,
或者更准确地说是物流，
um, function is this picture here.
嗯，功能就是这张照片。
So something that's squashes any real
所以有些东西会挤压任何真实的东西
number positive or negative into the range zero to one.
正数或负数在0到1的范围内。
It gives you a probability output.
它为您提供概率输出。
Um, these- this use of this, um,
嗯，这些 - 这个用这个，嗯，
logistic function was really really common in early neural nets.
逻辑函数在早期神经网络中确实很常见。
If you go back to '80s, '90s neural nets,
如果你回到80年代，'90年代的神经网络，
there were, um, sigmoid functions absolutely everywhere.
嗯，sigmoid功能绝对无处不在。
Um, in more recent times,
嗯，在最近的时代，
90 percent of the time nobody uses
90％的时间没有人使用
this and they've been found to sort of actually work quite poorly.
这一点，他们被发现实际上很糟糕。
The only place these are used is when you
这些使用的唯一地方就是你
actually want a value between zero and one is your output.
实际上想要一个介于零和一之间的值是你的输出。
So we'll talk later about how you have gating in networks,
所以我们稍后会谈谈你如何在网络中进行门控，
and so gating as a place where you want to have a probability between two things.
所以把门控作为你想要在两件事之间发生概率的地方。
And then you will use one of those,
然后你将使用其中一个，
but you use some absolutely nowhere else.
但你绝对没有其他地方使用。
Um, here is the tanh curve.
嗯，这是tanh曲线。
Um, so the formula for tanh, um,
嗯，所以tanh的公式，嗯，
looks like a scary thing with thoughts of exponentials in it,
看起来像一个可怕的东西，其中有指数的想法，
and it doesn't really look much like a logistic curve whatsoever.
而且它看起来并不像一条逻辑曲线。
Um, but if you um dig up your math textbook you can convince yourself that
嗯，但如果你挖掘数学教科书，你可以说服自己
a tanh curve is actually exactly the same as
tanh曲线实际上完全相同
the logistic curve apart from you multiply it by two,
除了你之外的逻辑曲线乘以2，
so it has a range of two rather than one,
所以它有两个而不是一个，
and you shift it down line.
然后你把它降低了。
So, this is sort of just a re-scaled logistic.
所以，这只是一个重新缩放的物流。
There's now symmetric between one and minus one,
现在在一和减一之间是对称的，
and the fact that some metric in the output actually helps
以及输出中的某些指标实际上有帮助的事实
a lot for putting into neural networks. Um.
投入神经网络的很多东西。嗯。
So, tanh's, are still reasonably widely used
所以，tanh's仍然被广泛使用
in quite a number of places um in um your networks.
在很多地方你都是你的网络。
So, tanh should be a friend of yours and you should know about that.
所以，tanh应该是你的朋友，你应该知道这一点。
But you know, one of the bad things about using
但是你知道，使用它的一个坏处
um transcendental functions like the sigmoid or tanh is,
像sigmoid或tanh这样的先验函数是，
you know, they involve this expensive math operations um that slow you down.
你知道，他们涉及这种昂贵的数学运算，这会减慢你的速度。
Like, it's sort of a nuisance to be kind
就像，善待一样令人讨厌
of computing exponentials and tanh's in your computer,
计算指数和计算机中的指数，
things are kind of slow.
事情有点慢。
So people started um playing around with ways
所以人们开始蠢蠢欲动
to make things faster and so someone came up with this idea like,
为了让事情更快，所以有人想出这个想法，
maybe we could come up with a hard tanh,
也许我们可以拿出一个坚硬的坦克，
um where it's just sort of flat out here
嗯，这里有点平坦
and then it has a linear slope and then it's flat at the top.
然后它有一个线性斜率，然后它在顶部是平的。
You know, it sort of looks like a tanh but we just squared it off.
你知道，它看起来像是一个坦然但我们只是将它平方。
Um, and while this is really cheap to compute right, you say,
嗯，虽然这对你的计算来说真的很便宜，但是你说，
x less than minus one,
x小于-1，
return minus one, return plus one or just return the number.
返回减1，返回加1或只返回数字。
No complex transcendentals.
没有复杂的超验主义。
The funny thing is,
有趣的是，
it turns out that this actually works pretty well.
事实证明，这实际上运作得很好。
You might be scared and you might justifiably be
你可能会感到害怕而且你可能是理所当然的
scared because if you start thinking about gradients,
害怕，因为如果你开始考虑渐变，
once you're over here,
一旦你到了这里，
there's no gradient, right?
没有渐变，对吗？
It's completely flat at zero.
零完全平坦。
So, things go dead as soon as they're at one of the ends.
所以，一旦他们处于其中一个目的，事情就会消失。
So, it's sort of important to stay in this middle section at least for
所以，至少留在这个中间部分是很重要的
a while and then its just got a slope of one, right?
一段时间然后它只有一个斜坡，对吧？
It's a constant slope of one.
这是一个恒定的斜率。
But this is enough of a linearity that actually it
但这实际上足够线性
works well in neural networks and you can train neural networks.
在神经网络中运行良好，你可以训练神经网络。
So, that's sent the whole field in the opposite direction and people thought,
所以，这是整个领域向相反的方向发送的，人们认为，
oh, if that works,
哦，如果有效，
maybe we can make things even simpler.
也许我们可以让事情更简单。
And that led to the now famous what's referred to [inaudible] as ReLU.
这导致现在着名的[听不清]被称为ReLU。
So there is a mistake in my editing there,
所以我在那里编辑有一个错误，
delete off hard tanh.
删除硬坦克。
That was in slides by mistake.
那是错误的幻灯片。
[LAUGHTER] The ReLU unit,
[大笑] ReLU单位，
everyone calls it ReLU which stands for rectified linear unit.
每个人都称之为ReLU，它代表整流线性单元。
So, the Re-, the ReLU is essentially the simplest non-linearity you can have.
因此，Re-，ReLU本质上是您可以拥有的最简单的非线性。
So the ReLU is zero,
所以ReLU是零，
slope zero as soon as you're in the negative regime and it's just a line slope one,
一旦你处于负面状态，斜率为零，它只是一个斜率斜率，
when you're in the positive regime.
当你处于积极的政权时。
I mean, when I first saw this,
我的意思是，当我第一次看到这个，
I mean, it's sort of blew my mind it could possibly work.
我的意思是，它有点让我觉得它可能会起作用。
Because it sort of, I guess,
因为它有点像，我想，
I was brought up on these sort of tanh's and sigmoids and the sorts of these arguments
我被这些tanh和sigmoids以及各种各样的论点所吸引
about the slope and you get these gradients and you can move around with the gradient.
关于斜率，你得到这些渐变，你可以随着渐变移动。
And how is it meant to work if half of this function just says
如果这个功能的一半只是说，它是如何工作的
output zero and no gradient and the other half is just this straight line.
输出零和没有梯度，另一半只是这条直线。
And in particular, when you're in the positive regime,
尤其是当你处于积极的政权时，
this is just an identity function.
这只是一个身份功能。
And, you know, I sort of argued before that if you just compose linear transforms,
并且，你知道，如果你只是组成线性变换，我之前会讨论一下，
you don't get any power but provided when this is the right-hand part of the regime.
你没有得到任何权力，但是当这是政权的右手部分时提供。
Since this is an identity function,
由于这是一个身份功能，
that's exactly what we're doing.
这正是我们正在做的事情。
We're just composing linear transforms.
我们只是在构成线性变换。
So you- you sort of believe it just can't possibly
所以你 - 你有点不相信它
work but it turns out that this works brilliantly.
工作，但事实证明，这工作出色。
And this is now by far
现在到目前为止
the default choice when people are building feed for deep networks.
人们为深层网络构建Feed时的默认选择。
That people use ReLU non-linearities and they are very fast,
人们使用ReLU非线性，它们非常快，
they train very quickly and they perform very well.
他们训练非常快，而且表现非常好。
And so, effectively, you know,
所以，实际上，你知道，
it is, it is simply just each u-,
它只是每个u-，
depending on the inputs,
取决于输入，
each unit is just either dead or it's passing things on as an identity function.
每个单位要么已经死了，要么就是作为身份功能传递。
But that's enough of lini-,
但这足够了lini-，
non-linearity that you can do
你可以做的非线性
arbitrary function approximation still with a deep learning network.
任意函数逼近仍然具有深度学习网络。
And people now make precisely the opposite argument which is,
人们现在正好相反的论点是，
because this unit just has a slope of one over it's non-zero range, that means,
因为这个单位在它的非零范围内只有一个斜率，这意味着，
the gradient is past spec very efficiently to
梯度非常有效地过去了
the inputs and therefore the models train very efficiently whereas,
输入，因此模型非常有效地训练，而，
when you are with these kind of curves,
当你使用这种曲线时，
when you're over here, there's very little slope so your models might train very slowly.
当你在这里时，坡度非常小，所以你的模型可能会非常缓慢地训练。
Okay. So, you know,
好的。所以你知道，
for feed-forward network, try this before you try anything else.
对于前馈网络，请在尝试其他任何操作之前尝试此操作。
But there's sort of then been a sub literature that says,
但是有一些子文献说，
well, maybe that's too simple and we could do a bit better.
好吧，也许这太简单了，我们可以做得更好。
And so that led to the leaky ReLU which said,
因此导致泄漏的ReLU说，
"Maybe we should put a tiny bit of slope over here so it's not completely dead."
“也许我们应该在这里放一点斜坡，这样它就不会完全死了。”
So you can make it something like one,
所以你可以做到像一个，
one 100th as the slope of this part.
一百分之一作为这部分的斜率。
And then people had, well,
然后人们有，好吧，
let's build off that,
让我们建立起来，
maybe we could actually put another parameter into
也许我们真的可以把另一个参数放进去
our neural network and we could have a parametric ReLU.
我们的神经网络，我们可以有一个参数ReLU。
So, there's some slope over here but we're also going to
所以，这里有一些斜坡，但我们也会去
backpropagate into our non-linearity which has this extra alpha parameter,
反向传播到我们的非线性中，它具有这个额外的alpha参数，
which is how ma- much slope it has.
这是它有多大的坡度。
And so, variously people have used these,
所以，各种各样的人都使用过这些，
you can sort of find 10 papers on archive where people say,
你可以在人们说的存档上找到10篇论文，
you can get better results from using one or other of these.
使用其中一个或另一个可以获得更好的结果。
You can also find papers where people said it made
你也可以找到人们所说的论文
no difference for them versus just using a ReLU.
与仅使用ReLU相比，它们没有区别。
So, I think basically,
所以，我认为基本上，
you can start off with a ReLU and work from there.
你可以从ReLU开始，然后在那里工作。
Yes. So, parameter initialization,
是。那么，参数初始化，
it's when, so, when we have these matrices and parameters in our model,
因此，当我们在模型中有这些矩阵和参数时，
it's vital, vital, vital,
它至关重要，至关重要，
that you have to initialize those parameter weights with small random values.
您必须使用小的随机值初始化这些参数权重。
This was precisely the lesson that
这正是教训
some people hadn't discovered when it came to final project time.
有些人在最后的项目时间没有发现。
So I'll emphasize it is vital, vital.
所以我要强调它至关重要，至关重要。
So, if you just start off with the weights being zero,
所以，如果你刚开始权重为零，
you kind of have these complete symmetries,
你有这些完整的对称性，
right, that everything will be calculated the same,
对，一切都会计算相同，
everything will move the same and you're not actually training
一切都会移动，你实际上并没有训练
this complex network with a lot of units that are specializing to learn different things.
这个复杂的网络有很多单位专门学习不同的东西。
So, somehow, you have to break the symmetry and we
所以，不知何故，你必须打破对称性和我们
do that by giving small random weights.
通过给予小的随机权重来做到这一点
So, you know, there's sort of some fine points.
所以，你知道，有一些优点。
When you have biases,
当你有偏见时，
you may as well just start them at Zero,
你也可以在Zero开始吧
as neutral and see how the system learn the bias that you want et cetera.
保持中立，看看系统如何学习你想要的偏见等等。
But in general, the weights you want to initialize to small random values.
但通常，您要将权重初始化为小的随机值。
You'll find in PyTorch or other deep learning practi- packages,
您可以在PyTorch或其他深度学习实践中找到，
a common initialization that's used and often recommended is this Xavier Initialization.
使用并经常推荐的常见初始化是此Xavier初始化。
And so, the trick of this is that,
所以，这样做的诀窍是，
for a lot of models and a lot of places,
对于很多模特和很多地方，
think of some of these things like these ones and these,
想到这些东西，比如这些，以及
you'd like the values in the network to sort of stay small,
你希望网络中的值保持小，
in this sort of middle range here.
在这里的中间范围。
And well, if you kind of have a matrix with big values in it
好吧，如果你有一个具有重要价值的矩阵
and you multiply a vector by this matrix,
然后用这个矩阵乘以一个向量，
you know, things might get bigger.
你知道，事情可能会变得更大。
And then if you put in through another layer,
然后，如果你通过另一层，
it'll get bigger again and then sort of everything
它会再次变大，然后排序
will be too big and you will have problems.
会太大你会有问题。
So, really, Xavier Initialization is seeking to avoid that by saying,
所以，真的，Xavier Initialization正试图通过说，
how many inputs are there to this node?
这个节点有多少输入？
How many outputs are there?
有多少输出？
We want to sort of temp it down the initialization based on the inputs
我们希望根据输入对初始化进行排序
and the outputs because effectively we'll be using this number that many times.
和输出，因为有效地我们将多次使用这个数字。
It's a good thing to use, you can use that.
这是一件好事，你可以使用它。
Optimizers. Up till now,
优化。至目前为止，
we saw, just talked about plain SGD.
我们看到，刚才谈到普通的SGD。
You know, normally plain SGD actually works just fine.
你知道，通常普通的SGD实际上工作得很好。
But often if you want to use just plain SGD,
但通常如果你想使用普通的SGD，
you have to spend time tuning the learning rate,
你必须花时间调整学习率，
that alpha that we multiplied the gradient by.
那个我们乘以渐变的alpha。
For complex nets and situations or to avoid worry,
对于复杂的网和情况或避免担心，
there's sort of now this big family and more sophisticated adaptive optimizers.
现在有一个大家庭和更复杂的自适应优化器。
And so, effectively they're scaling the parameter adjustment by accumulated gradients,
因此，他们有效地通过累积渐变来缩放参数调整，
which have the effect that they learn per parameter learning rates.
它们具有每个参数学习率学习的效果。
So that they can see which parameters would be useful to move
这样他们就可以看到哪些参数对移动有用
more and which one is less depending on the sensitivity of those parameters.
取决于这些参数的灵敏度，更多，哪一个更少。
So, where things are flat,
所以，在事情平平的地方，
you can be trying to move quickly.
你可以尝试快速行动。
Where things are bouncing around a lot,
事物在很多地方蹦蹦跳跳，
you are going to be trying to move just a little so as not to overshoot.
你将试图移动一点点，以免过冲。
And so, there's a whole family of these; Adagrad,
所以，这里有一整个家庭; Adagrad，
RMSprop, Adam, there are actually other ones.
RMSprop，Adam，实际上还有其他的。
There's Adam Max and whole lot of them.
有亚当麦克斯和他们的很多。
I mean, Adam is one fairly reliable one that many people use and that's not bad.
我的意思是，亚当是一个相当可靠的人，许多人使用，这并不坏。
And then one more slide and I'm done.
然后又一张幻灯片，我已经完成了。
Yes, so learning rates.
是的，所以学习率。
So, normally you have to choose a learning rate.
所以，通常你必须选择一个学习率。
So, one choice is just have a constant learning rate.
因此，一种选择只是具有恒定的学习率。
You pick a number, may be 10 to the minus three and say that's my learning rate.
你选了一个数字，可能是10到负3，并说这是我的学习率。
You want your learning rate to be order of magnitude, right.
你希望你的学习率是数量级的。
If your learning rate is too big,
如果你的学习率太大，
your model might diverge or not converge because it just sort of leaps you around by
你的模型可能会分歧或不会聚合，因为它只会让你跳跃
huge cram movements and you completely miss the good parts of your function space.
巨大的补习班动作，你完全错过了你的功能空间的好部分。
If your model, if your learning rate is too small,
如果你的模特，如果你的学习率太小，
your model may not train by the assignment deadline and then you'll be unhappy.
你的模特可能不会在作业截止日期前训练，然后你会不高兴。
So, you saw that, you know,
所以，你看到了，你知道，
commonly people sort of try powers of 10 and sees how it looks, right.
通常人们尝试10的力量，看看它的外观，对吧。
They might try, you know, 0,01, 0,001,
他们可能会尝试，0,01,0,001，
0,0001 and see, look at how the loss is declining and see what seems to work.
0,0001，看看，看看损失是如何下降，看看似乎有效。
In general, you want to use
一般来说，你想使用
the fastest learning rate that isn't making things become unstable.
最快的学习率，不会使事情变得不稳定。
Commonly, you could get better results by decreasing the learning rate as you train.
通常，您可以通过在训练时降低学习率来获得更好的结果。
So, sometimes people just do that by hand.
所以，有时人们只是手工做到这一点。
So, we use the term epoch for a full pass
因此，我们使用术语epoch进行完整传递
through your training data and people might say,
通过您的培训数据，人们可能会说，
half the learning rate after every three epochs
每三个时期后学习率的一半
as you train and that can work pretty well.
当你训练，那可以很好地工作。
You can use formulas to get per epoch tra- learning rates.
您可以使用公式来获取每个时期的学习率。
There are even fancier methods.
甚至有更高级的方法。
You can look up cyclic learning rates online if you want,
如果需要，您可以在线查询循环学习率
which sort of actually makes the learning rates
哪种实际上使学习率
sometimes bigger and then sometimes smaller,
有时更大，有时更小，
and people have found that that can be useful for getting you out
而且人们发现这对你说出来很有帮助
of bad regions in interesting ways.
有趣的方式的坏地区。
The one other thing to know is,
另一件要知道的是，
if you're using one of the fancier optimizers,
如果您正在使用其中一个更好的优化器，
they still ask you for a learning rate but that learning rate is
他们仍然会问你学习率，但学习率是
the initial learning rate which typically the optimizer will shrink as you train.
初始学习速率，通常优化器会在您训练时缩小。
So, commonly if you're using something like Adam,
所以，通常如果你使用像Adam这样的东西，
you might be starting off by saying the learning rate is 0,1,
你可能会开始说学习率是0,1，
so of a bigger number and it will be shrinking it later as the training goes along.
这样一个更大的数字，随着训练的进行，它将会缩小。
Okay, all done. See you next week.
好的，一切都完成了。下周见。